Ready?
Ready?
Welcome to the second part of the program.
Welcome to the second part of the program.
The second part of the program is about the knowledge of the second month.
The second part of the program is about the knowledge of the second month.
Let's start.
Let's start.
Please welcome the vice president of the Wang Hui Jun.
Please welcome the vice president of the Wang Hui Jun.
Thank you for your time.
Thank you for your time.
Good evening, everyone.
Good evening, everyone.
Thank you for joining us today.
Thank you for joining us today.
Thank you for your time.
Thank you for your time.
Today we are very happy to invite you to the Institute of Biochemistry, Academia Sinica
今天我們非常高興請到我們中央研究院生化所
Professor Lin Junhong, Researcher of the Institute of Biochemistry
生物化學研究所的研究員林俊宏教授
Let me introduce Professor Lin a little bit, although you may have one
我稍微介紹一下這個林教授雖然各位所上可能有一張
However, there is a bit of information on this that is not quite correct.
不過這個上面有一點這個不太正確的一些這個資料
That Professor Lin Junhong graduated from the Chemistry Department of our National Taiwan University
那個林俊宏教授是我們這個臺灣大學化學系畢業
So is it my junior brother or someone called me just now?
所以算是我的師弟還是剛才有人叫我叫他是
What is it called Tang? Brother Tang, some people say that I am Tang Gong or something
叫什麼唐什麼唐哥那有人說那我是唐工還是什麼
anyway, so I'm a grown-up
anyway 所以我算是長大一輩了
After he graduated from the Chemistry Department of National Taiwan University in 1990,
那他在臺大化學系1990年畢業以後
Just go to the Scripps Research Institute in the United States
就到這個美國的Scripps Research Institute
It was a very distinguished
那是在美國聖地亞哥的一個非常傑出的
the research unit
這個研究單位
academic unit
學術單位
you may
各位可能
Some are not clear, but if I say that Dean Weng used to work there
有些不太清楚不過我如果講翁院長以前在那裡任職
in the back
在回
Before our middle school
我們中院院之前啊
When he was dean he was in
當院長的時候他是在
Scripps
Scripps
Our teacher Lin Junhong is here
我們林俊宏老師就是在
Under the guidance of Dean Weng
翁院長的這個指導之下
received this Ph.D.
拿到了這個博士學位
then
然後就
Arrived on the east coast of Harvard in the United States
到了這個美國的哈佛東岸
From West Coast to East Coast Harvard University
從西岸跑到東岸哈佛大學
of this
的這個
It's a medical school
算是醫學院啦
This one is very famous with Chris Walsh
這個跟Chris Walsh一個很有名的
this
這個
The professor is also doing a very good job in developing drugs
教授啊也是在開發藥物方面做得非常好的
so we are
所以我們在
There is a saying in academia that says
學術界有一個有一個話就是說
his portal is very good
他的門戶非常好
The Right Pedigree
The Right Pedigree
after that come back
那回來以後
quilt
被
At that time, the director of our mythology
那時候我們神話所所長
Director Liu Derong
劉德榮所長啊
Recruit back
Recruit回來
Since then, he has performed very well.
那回來以後就表現非常的優秀
that's a lot
那得了很多
many awards
很多的獎
then this
那麼這個
Here, for example, in
這邊其實比如說在
Scripts already got a lot
Scripts就已經拿到很
nice award
很好的一個獎
The trustee then transmits the academic award
然後理事傳送這個學術獎
This is not easy
這個也很不容易的話
Because you are applying for this award in Taiwan
因為你在台灣要申請這個獎
It seems that our comprehensive hospital only gets one
一年我們綜合院好像只拿到一個
so he got the award too
所以他也得了這個獎
so recently
那麼最近呢
He also got our Li Tiande
他也得了我們的李天德
he is a drug company
他是一個藥的公司
He has an established some young academic awards
他有一個設立了一些年輕學術獎
he also got the award
他也得到這個獎
Also very famous internationally
還有在國際上也非常有名
He also got us a
他也拿到我們一個叫做
An Academic Alliance of Developing Countries
開發中國家的一個學術聯盟
We are Pros
我們叫Pros
he also got the young man award
他也得了這個年輕獎
So it's all young young young
所以這裡面都是年輕年輕年輕
so he's our ten youngest
所以他是我們的十大年輕
what is it call
叫什麼
top ten potential figures
十大潛力人物
So it's not just potential
所以其實已經不只是潛力
he is doing very well now
他現在表現非常好
So the potential has been fully realized
所以潛力已經完全出來了
so we are very happy to have this opportunity
所以我們非常高興有這個機會
This information says
這個資料上面說
it's an associate researcher at the manager center
它是經理中心的副研究員
That's wrong, now a researcher
這不對啦 現在已經是研究員
National Taiwan University is also a professor, not an associate professor
台大也是教授 不是副教授
So this data
所以這個資料
I'm going back to this
我回去要跟這個
Was it made by the secretary team?
是秘書組弄的嗎
I'm going to integer integer
我要去整數整數
How to use old data to share with others
怎麼拿舊的資料來跟人家
Excuse me
不好意思
But today he's going to make us a
不過今天他要給我們做一個
I believe sir is a brilliant actor
我相信先生很精采的演員長
called health medicine tonic
叫健康藥補藥
I now think he was super wrong
我現在以為他是超錯了
is the name of the movie
是電影的名字
But he's coming to tell us in a simple way
不過他要來跟我們用深入淺出的一個方式
Come talk to us about drug development
來跟我們介紹藥物開發
what's the matter with this aspect
這一方面是怎麼一回事
have some secrets
有一些秘心
So he's coming to make a
所以他要來跟我們做一個
It's an in-depth introduction
算是深入淺出的介紹
Today's Liberty Times
今天的《自由時報》
In fact, his secret has been leaked
其實已經洩漏了他的秘密
So I wrote a little report in it
所以寫了一段小小的報告在裡面
Then we warmly welcome Professor Lin
那我們就熱烈歡迎林教授
Thank you Vice President Wang
謝謝王副院長
can you hear my voice
我的聲音大家聽得到嗎
First time using this microphone
第一次用這種麥克風
they say i look like mike jackson
他們說我很像麥克風傑克森
But I'm not that handsome
不過我沒有那麼帥
skin is not so white
皮膚沒有那麼白
First of all, I am very grateful to Vice President Wang for the opportunity
首先我非常謝謝王副院長的機會
Vice President Wang was actually the head of the house who was on us before.
王副院長其實之前他是在我們身上的房所長
He actually promoted me
他其實就很提拔我
Today I am also very grateful to Wang for the opportunity
今天我也很謝謝王的機會
Because I am doing drug development
因為我本身是在做藥物的開發方面
I usually collect some information
平常有收取一些資料
So when the secretary group informed me that
所以當秘書組通知我說
When you have this please let me talk about this aspect
有這個請我來講這方面的時候
Actually I was shocked
其實我嚇一跳
Because I see the presentation time is about 90 minutes
因為我看演講時間大概要90分鐘
usually i give speeches outside
通常我在外面給演講
I only have 40 minutes for my major
是我自己專業都只有40分鐘
Suddenly it's 90 minutes
突然要講到90分鐘
It's a bit of a mess
實在是有點亂了
So or I still collect some data
所以或者是我還是收取一些資料
let everyone share
讓大家來分享
So what am I going to talk about today?
那今天我要講什麼東西呢
what about first
那首先呢
Everyone seems to have a lot of this drug
大家看起來有很多很多的這個藥物
But I put this drug into a large category
那不過我把這個藥分的上了大類
first category
第一個大類
This drug is very likely to have something to do with our life-threatening
這藥物很肯跟我們的生命威脅有關係的
For example, when you are infected with bacteria inside
比如說你當裡面你細菌感染的時候
You may soon be off antibiotics
你可能馬上就要就要不用抗生素
that or
那或是說
For example, if you encounter cancer
比如說如果碰到癌症的時候
How do we take an anticancer drug like this
我們怎麼樣服用這樣子的一個抗癌藥物
This is life threatening
這是屬於跟生命威脅有關的
The second category is related to our quality of life
那第二類是跟我們生活品質有關係的
Say you gain weight
比如說你長胖一點
then i think you are no threat to your life
那我想你對你的生命沒有什麼威脅
Of course we want to be thinner
那當然我們希望瘦一點
so let me tell you
所以我跟各位講一下
about diet pills
有關於減肥藥
Well of course the Will cylinder
那當然這威爾缸
words for boys
對男生來講的話
Of course it is a serious disease
當然它是有重症雄風
That's Will Cylinder
那是威爾缸
That is to say, you may need to know that normal
那或是說各位可能要知道說平常
like our joints
比如說我們的關節
If you want to strengthen joint function, there is Hanan
想要加強關節功能的話有含安
or girls
或是說女生的
In our general cosmetics
我們一般的化妝品裡面
added uric acid
添加了不尿酸
I will introduce you
我會跟各位來做介紹
The third category is related to our daily life
第三類是跟我們日常生活
related drugs
相關的一些藥物
For example, in our life
比如說我們在生活中
south americans have some ailments
南美人會有一些病痛
how to take painkillers
怎麼吃了止痛藥
like aspirin or these
像阿斯比林或是這些
Proton these drugs
普拿騰這些藥物
In the end, I will talk about two meanings
那最後我會講兩個的意思
one is
一個就是
Thalidomide
Falidomide
this is in
這個是在
in the 50s and 6s
在50年六年代
famous drug
很有名的藥物
then it had a pretty tragic outcome
那它有一個蠻悲慘的結果
You may also
那各位可能也
It's what we usually see in newspapers now
就是我們一般我們現在常常在報紙上看到
academic unit
學術單位
Including our Academia Sinica or other universities
包括我們中研院或其他的大學
There is often a press release of some research and development results
常常會有一些研發成果的一個新聞稿
often talk about
常常會講到說
Such research and development results
這樣子的研發成果
may say expected
可能說預計
Maybe for example it will go into the development of a drug
可能比如說它會投入藥物的開發
May be available in 10 years
可能10年後上市
What the hell are these press releases?
那到底這些新聞稿
Of course it's a press release written by a reporter
當然它是由記者所寫的新聞稿
that may not be entirely true
那可能不見得是完全正確
But it's in every press release
不過它在每一個新聞稿
it told you
它告訴你的
It is said to be related to drug development
它是說跟藥物研發有關
what does that mean
那到底是在什麼意義
then i think last
那我想最後
Then I will give you some very simple introductions
然後跟各位來做一些很簡單的介紹
But at the very beginning, let me tell you something
那不過一開始的時候 我講跟各位來講一下
that is
就是說
this way
這個這樣
This is a prescription, it's my family's prescription.
這個是一個藥方處方單 是我家人的藥方處方單
I'm sorry because this isn't obvious by itself.
對不起 因為這個本身就不是很明顯
But generally speaking, if you say that in your daily life
不過就是說一般來講 如果說你在日常生活上
you
你
Get a prescription first, for example, recently everyone
拿到一個處方先 比如說最近大家
cold
感冒
Then of course you go back to the clinic to get some medicine
那當然你回去診所拿個藥
After taking the medicine, you are
那拿藥之後你是
Just obediently listen to the doctor's instructions
就很乖乖的聽醫生指示
The instructions say to eat several times a day or eat raw liver
指示說一天要吃幾次 或生肝吃
or anti eat
或反吃
Did you take a closer look at your
那你有沒有仔細去看看你的
What's in it?
這個裡面內容呢
Then I will give a speech today, of course
那我今天演講 當然
I though
我雖然
but impossible
不過不可能
I am not a doctor myself
我自己不是醫生
I won't tell you what medicine you should and should not take
我會不跟你講說什麼藥該什麼藥不該吃
You guys can't have listened to me for 90 minutes
各位也不可能聽了我90分鐘
You know what medicine to take when you give a speech
的演講就知道說要吃什麼藥
But I want you to be able to say
不過我希望各位能夠說
In the future, in your daily life, for example, if you see the drug list
將來你在日常生活中 比如說你看到藥單
At least I will care about the medicines you take
至少會關心一下 你吃的藥是有
what ingredients
什麼成分
Now that the Internet is developed
那現在網路發達
In the past you might have to look up books
以前你可能要去查書
Now you just look it up online
現在的話你只要上網一查一下
probably in
很可能就在
You'll know the answer in a minute or two
一兩分鐘之內就知道答案
There are two medicines here
那這邊有兩個藥
i want to tell you
我想跟各位講一下
One is keratomysine
一個是keratomysine
This is when my family member catches a cold
這個是我家人他感冒的時候
Medicines taken at the clinic
去診所拿的藥
keratomysine is an antibiotic
keratomysine是一種抗生素
Then the other semitidine is stomach medicine
那另外這個semitidine是胃藥
That probably means that the medicine contains
那很可能就是說這個藥裡面
it has some stomach irritating ingredients
它有一些對胃刺激的成分
So the doctor prescribed a semitidine
所以醫生開了一個semitidine
it is a stomach medicine
它是一個胃藥
gastric protection
胃藥保護胃的
The other three or four ingredients
那其他這三四種成分
is a component of Violet
是紫可化的一個成分
So let's get into the topic now
那我們現在就開始進入主題
the first topic is antibiotics
那第一個主題是抗生素
But in this part
不過在這部分的話
maybe say sorry
可能跟做個抱歉
Because of many drugs
因為很多的藥物呢
In fact, there are many complicated pharmacology involved in it.
其實裡面牽上很多很複雜的藥理
that many some nouns
那很多一些一些名詞
what about these nouns
那這些名詞呢
It's really hard for me to translate it one by one
我實在很難一個一個去把它翻譯
and many many English
而且很多很多英文
But of course I try to use
不過當然我盡量的用
Let me introduce you in a way
用方式來跟各位來做介紹
First of all, the first topic I want to talk about today is related to antibiotics.
那首先我今天要講的第一個主題是跟抗生素有關
What are antibiotics?
那什麼叫抗生素呢
Basically it's for bacterial infections when
基本上它是針對於細菌感染的時候
antibacterial
抗生素殺菌的
Of course, if you have a little
那當然如果各位稍微有
That is to say, if there is a little bit about this aspect
就是說對這方面有涉略的話
The first antibiotic was penicillin
第一個抗生素是潘尼西林
what about this topic
那對於這個主題呢
I might give you an introduction
我可能跟各位來做個介紹
who was the first inventor
誰是第一個的發明人
The first antibiotic was penicillin
第一個抗生素是潘尼西林
who is the inventor
誰是發明人
where does it work
那它的作用在哪裡
Because the bacteria we have today have invaded the human body
因為我們今天這個細菌已經侵略了人體
Then our medicine must be selective, of course.
那我們的藥當然要有選擇性
because our medicine
因為我們的藥物
actually a chemical
事實上是一種化學物質
if you eat it
那吃下去的話
what about the drug
這個藥物呢
hope it doesn't affect anyone
希望對人沒有影響
have an effect on bacteria
而對細菌有影響
So let me tell you about this later
所以這個我等一下跟你們講
How does it work?
它的作用的機制呢
It is related to the cell B of the bacteria
是跟細菌的細胞B有關
why wait a minute
為什麼等一下會解釋
how did it find out
它當初怎麼發現的
it's an interesting process
它是個很有趣的一個過程
i will explain
我會解釋一下
And because when it was discovered
然後因為發現的時候呢
The timing of this discovery was at
這個發現的時機是在
Before the Second World Mass in 1928
第二次世界大量之前在1928年
Then its research and development from the discovery
那它的研發從發現
be mass-produced in the end
到最後能夠大量生產
applied to human medicine
應用在人類的醫療上
In fact, it's time for the second mass
事實上是到了二次大量的時候
so what
所以呢
In fact many people say
事實上很多人都講說
What about an invention like this?
這樣子的一個發明呢
Actually changed the secondary world a lot
事實上改變了二次世界大量的
final result
最後的結果
why wait a minute
為什麼 等一下會稍微介紹一下
After the mass of the second world
那從二次世界大量以後
after
之後
Because of this success
因為這一方面的成功呢
So many pharmaceutical companies started
所以開始了很多藥廠
started some searching
開始了一些尋找
Are there other drug molecules
有沒有其他的藥物分子
that also has a bactericidal effect
那同樣具有殺菌的效果
And so began a chain of discoveries that began
所以開始有一連串的發現開始
And while there are many, many drugs
然後雖然有很多很多的藥物
with antibiotics
跟抗生素
are antibiotics are antibiotics
是抗生素是屬於抗生素
But what?
可是呢
as a result of our abuse
因為我們濫用的結果
Or the bacteria themselves are constantly de-evolving
或是說細菌本身有不斷的去演化
or there are constantly some strategies coming out
或有不斷的一些策略出來
So now we meet
所以呢我們現在碰到
The biggest problem is a problem of drug resistance
最大問題是一個抗藥性的問題
Protect the most points
保護最分
On the topic of public security, I will use these projects to give you an introduction
公安這個主題我用這幾個項目來跟各位來做一個介紹
before that
那在這之前呢
Let me tell you about the medicine in Huang'an
來跟各位講一下這個皇安內的藥物
Because of the medicine in Huang'an
因為皇安內的藥物呢
In fact, before the invention of adenoids
事實上是在抗爭素發明以前
That
那
before discovery antibiotic
before discovery antibiotic
A drug just before aventin was invented
就在抗爭素發明之前的一個藥物
What about Huang'an's medicine?
那皇安的藥物呢
By itself we say that he is a drug of resistin
本身我們說他是一個抗爭素的藥物
Why didn't we say he wasn't a resistin?
為什麼我們不是說他不是一個抗爭素呢
Because Huangan's medicine now knows that he is
因為皇安的藥物現在已經知道他是
the growth of a fine smoke
一次細菸的生長
so when you
所以呢當你
When the liver is infected with small fine tobacco, you use Huang'an medicine
小細菸肝染的時候你用皇安內藥物
That's Huang'an medicine?
那是皇安內藥物呢
In fact, it can temporarily prevent the growth of thin smoke so fast
事實上是可以讓細菸暫時的生長不要這麼快
because if everyone knows
因為如果大家如果知道的話
If the growth of thin smoke is based on Daanmen
細菸的生長如果以大安門來講的話
Is after 20 minutes a generation can start reinstatement
是20分鐘之後一個世代就可以開始復職
20 minutes grows very fast
20分鐘生長非常快
So if you take Huang'an medicine
所以你服用皇安內藥物的話
In fact he's mainly targeting his folic acid synthesis
事實上他主要是針對他葉酸的合成
Growth of folic acid into pholate
葉酸的生長成pholate
What about Huang'an's medicine?
那皇安的藥物呢
So he is because of the ability to block fine smoke
所以他是因為阻斷細菸的這個
So bacteria because they need folic acid nutrients
所以細菌因為需要葉酸的營養成分
so it will grow suppressed
所以它會 它生長受到壓抑
At this time, if your immune system is strong enough
這個時候如果你免疫系統夠強的時候
If bacteria grow repressed
如果細菌如果被壓抑的生長的話
If your immune system is strong enough to handle it
那你免疫系統足以應付的話
Then your bacterial infection can of course be cured
那你這個細菌的感染當然就可以被治癒
So what about the internal medicine? It's not an antibiotic.
所以滑內藥呢 它並不是抗生素
Because it is, it can only be said that it is a drug that can resist vitamins
因為它是 它只能說它是可以抗維生物的一個藥物
But before the invention of this antibiotic
可是在於這個抗生素的發明之前
It is a drug that is commonly used by others.
它是在普遍被人家來使用的一個藥物 滑內藥物
Then the main invention came from this dye
那這個主要的發明是從這個染藥裡面得來的
Therefore, the Huanei drug found at that time was indeed
所以當時找到的滑內藥物它的確確
inhibits the growth of bacteria
會有抑制細菌的生長的時候
So they started looking for it from a lot of dyes
所以他們開始從很多的染藥裡面去尋找
Is there an active ingredient
有沒有一個活性成分
You all know that at that time
那各位也知道說在那個時候
In fact, the prevention and control industry is very developed
事實上是防治工業非常發達
so a lot of dye a lot of dye
所以有很多染料 很多染料
Then look for these drugs from the dye
那從染料裡面去尋找這些藥物
What about the first xanthamines?
那第一個黃胺類藥物呢
In history it is here
在歷史上就是在這個
The entire medical surplus is called
整個醫療有餘的叫做
Pontosil is the drug
Pontosil 就是這個藥物
Do you know why it is called yellow amines?
各位知道它為什麼叫黃胺類
Because its English name is Sophora
因為它的英文叫Sophora
Because it mainly contains this xanthic acid
因為它主要有這個黃酸類
xanthates and then it adds an amine
黃酸類 然後它加了一個胺
Drugs that are slightly not called yellow amines
稍微不會叫黃胺類的藥物
Pontosil is what we now know is a
Pontosil就是我們現在知道的就是一個
A first drug of the yellow amine class
一個黃胺類的第一個藥物
to fight bacterial growth
來對抗細菌的生長
That in fact it is a Protide
那事實上它是一個Protide
That is to say, the drug is taken into the body
也就是說這個藥物吃到身體裡面
Why is it called Protide?
為什麼什麼叫Protide
a subjunctive of the drug
也就是藥物的一個潛倒物
That is to say, it has no function
也就是說它本身沒有功能
but eat into the body
可是吃到身體裡面
Influenced by our body's performance metabolism
受到我們身體的性能代謝的作用
it is broken down
它被分解
The decomposed substances are still the ingredients of the drug.
那分解出來的物質還是那個藥物的成分
So it is said to be a drug lead
所以它我們說是一個藥物的先導物
Precursor Protide
先屈物Protide
That drug is also very famous
那這個藥物也非常有名
because I just said
因為我剛剛講過就是說
He was before the invention of the resistance number
他在抗爭數被發明之前
He is used to fight bacterial infections
他是用來對抗細菌的感染的
Of course he can't sterilize
那當然他不能殺菌
What about the most famous example?
那最有名的例子呢
is in
是在
That is to say, his example is in
就是說他的例子在在
early days of war two
二次戰爭的早期
war two because
二次戰爭因為
The Second World War probably started around 1940
二次戰爭大概大概是在1940年開始
in the early days because
那早期的時候因為
when war breaks out
一旦發生戰爭的時候
There will be many casualties on the field
在場上會有很多的傷亡
So if you ever watch those war movies
所以如果你有去看那些戰爭片
like saving private lane
比如說搶救雷恩大兵
or some war movies
或是一些戰爭片的時候
If you listen carefully to his dialogue
你如果仔細聽他的對白
you will listen carefully when that
你會仔細聽的話當那個
When the soldiers are defeated by me, they will call conscripts, and then they will say "sweep the light file, sweep the light file or sweep the light file"
士兵我打倒的時候他們就會叫義務兵然後就喊說掃光檔掃光檔或是掃光檔
That is to say
也就是說
He's hurt, hurry up and use this drug
他受傷了趕快使用這個藥物來
to treat his wound
來對他傷口做處理
in the early days
在早期的時候
is very important to use
是非常重要的一個用
The other most famous is
那另外最有名的是
He once saved the prime minister this autumn
他曾經救了這個秋季的首相
s life
的生命
why
為什麼呢
Because I just told him that on the battlefield
因為剛剛講過他的戰場上
just a lot of soldiers
就很多士兵
Other guns also include autumn
他槍子也包括秋季
Why? This is of course a picture of Churchill
為什麼呢?這個當然就是邱吉爾的照片
Everyone, if you look at the photos of historical phenomena
各位如果去看歷史現象的照片的話
He already has a tall hat we're used to
他已經有我們很習慣戴一個高高的帽子
But Churchill
可是邱吉爾
Nathan Churchill
那當邱吉爾
because at the time in the UK
因為當時在英國
Of course he is here
他當然他這個是在
he is a brelian
他是一個布雷連島
At that time, Britain had many colonies
那當英國那時候占有很多的殖民地
including north africa
包括北非
Everyone knows that Germany was
那各位知道德國那時候
Except in aggression in the European battlefield
除了在侵略在歐洲戰場之外
They go to fight, say, Belgium, Holland, France
他們去打比如說打比利時、荷蘭、法國
Even ended up going to Russia
甚至最後打到俄國去
In addition, Germany at that time
那另外呢德國那時候
Originally based on British colonies on the other side of Africa
一開始基於英國在非洲那邊的殖民地
At that time, Britain had a lot of colonies in North Africa
那英國那時候在北非有一大堆殖民地
Then Germany will be killed
那德國他就害了
His most famous tank army
他最有名的那個坦克軍
The general of the Tank Club is called Longmener
坦克社的將軍叫龍門爾
He uses the tank company
他用坦克社公司呢
Use them to say Longmener
用他們就說龍門爾
he is a stranger
他是當陌s
He uses tank club tactics
他用坦克社戰術呢
can rarely north africa
可以很少北非
Because the terrain in North Africa is flat
因為北非那邊的地形是平遠
So the war is already urgent
所以戰爭已經很緊急了
So autumn is also very tense
所以秋季也很緊張
He went to Tunisia in North Africa to investigate
他跑到北非圖尼西亞去訪查
Because of course if the leader goes, it can calm down the troops
因為當然如果首領去的時候可以鎮定軍心
When I went, I wanted to say
去的時候本來是想說
Positive economics to see if the British army can
正份經濟看能不能英國的軍隊
Able to face off against the German army
能夠跟德國軍隊突襄對峙
I never thought that when he was in Tunicia
就沒想到他在圖尼西亞的時候
he has an infection
他發生了感染
this infection is very serious
這感染非常嚴重
So at that time, a sick notice was issued.
所以那個時候已經有發出病通知了
So of course he can't let Germany know
所以當然他是不能讓德國知道
germany they are happy to say
德國他們很高興說
British Prime Minister may soon be knocked out
英國首相可能快敲掉
So by that time his daughter had already flown from the UK
所以那個時候他的女兒已經從英國搭飛機
to Tunicia beside him
到圖尼西亞在他旁邊
Because at that time Churchill was already ill.
因為那個時候丘吉爾已經是臥病不起了
A sickness notice has been issued
已經發出病為通知了
didn't expect them
就沒想到他們
That is to say, the doctor Churchill used this wind-sweeping dragon
就是說丘吉爾這個醫生就使用了這個掃風龍
Because at that time, Panning Xining had not yet been mass-produced.
因為那個時候潘寧細寧是還沒有量產的
I'll talk about it later
我等一下會講到
So they are using Ponosio
所以他們使用的是Ponosio
It turned out that Churchill's life was successfully saved.
結果能夠成功拯救丘吉爾的這個性命
That means he's responding to the drug, too.
就是說他對這個藥物有反應也是一樣
It's his blood that doesn't work
就是他的沒血有作用
so he can come alive
所以他可以活過來
then later
那後來
Because he can't announce it during the war
因為他這個是戰爭的時候不能公布
But he followed the radio in the newspaper
可是他在報紙上跟在廣播裡面
he just talked
他就講說
i have a small situation in tunicia
我在圖尼西亞有一個小狀況
But luckily it’s because it’s Flaming
可是還好是因為那個是Flaming
Because Flaming is a British Panlin series invention
因為Flaming是英國人的盤林系列發明
so saved my life
所以救了我的生命
Because he doesn't admit that Pontos has
因為他不承認是Pontos有
Because Pontos has this drug
因為Pontos有這個藥
It's the yellow and blue drug, Bayer in Germany
是黃藍藥物的是德國拜爾在
So in terms of this moral
所以以這個道德來講的話
Of course because Britain was at war with Germany
當然因為當時英國跟德國在作戰
He absolutely can't say it's a drug invented by the Germans
他絕對不能說這是德國人發明的藥
he must have said
他一定就說
i have a problem in north africa
我在北非出了狀況
Fortunately, it was given to me by Flaming's protest department.
那還好是Flaming的抗爭處給我的
saved my life
拯救了我的生命
So but the fact
所以不過這個事實上
Later Deng Ming actually
後來鄧明事實上
Churchill killed Huang
邱吉爾是殺了黃
Their government affairs killed Huang
他們政務殺了黃
In fact, it was the Germans Bayer who produced it
事實上是德國人拜爾他們產生的
This yellow and blue drug saved Churchill's life
這個黃藍藥物救了邱吉爾的生命
It's a very famous story
這是非常有名的一個故事
then again
那再來
His name is Penningsillin
他叫這個潘寧西林
I just talked about Penning Xilin
那潘寧西林我剛剛講過
He is the first resistance aid in our human body
他是我們人類體上第一個抗爭助
It's a drug that can treat bacterial infections
他就是能夠來對付細菌感染的藥物
can be sterilized
可以殺菌
The inventor, of course, was Alexander Freyming
那當然發明人是Alexander Freyming
That's Freyming
就是那個Freyming
Because of his later contributions to human medicine
因為後來他對人類醫療上的貢獻
He was called SIR by the wind
他被風絕叫SIR
That's this penning cillin
那是這個潘寧西林
Our question is of course Penningsillin
我們的質疑當然就是潘寧西林
He is usually called Cin-E-S-U
他通常我們也稱為叫Cin-E-S-U
His structure is quite unique
他的結構是個蠻獨特的結構
That's for chemistry
那對於化學上來講
Because of his four-five-ring structure
因為他這個四五環的架構
is a very strange
是個非常奇怪的
when he invented
當時他的發明的時候
no one believes in this structure
沒有人相信這個結構
So until 1928
所以一直到1928年
Freyming discovered
Freyming發現了
found out
有發現一下
Afterwards they managed to save the dormitory
之後他們有成功的去存化這個教宿
Structural identification of Nathan's chemical
那他的化學物的結構鑑定
I just said this about chemicals
我剛剛講過對化學物的這樣
it is a very unstable structure
它是個非常不穩定的結構
until the 1950s
一直到1950年代
There's Dorothy that
有Dorothy那個
good
好
He just used x-ray to explain
他才用x-ray來解釋
to really decide on his structure
來真正的決定他的結構
But why is he called Omeshu
那不過為什麼他叫青梅樹
Because Fleming knows
因為傅蘭明他知道
He found this plum fungus
他找到這個梅菌
Plum fungus
叫青梅菌
Because of Plum fungus
因為有青梅菌
The identified chemical
所分明的這個化學物質
green plum tree
就叫青梅樹
So usually you will see in literature or books
所以通常你在文獻上或書籍上會看到
Some people call it Penisening
有人稱為Penisening
Because or called green plum tree
因為或者叫青梅樹
Actually he's just the same thing
事實上他只是同一個東西
Then this is our Dr. Fleming
那這就是我們傅蘭明的博士
And then of course their interest in human
然後當然他們對人類利益上
made a great contribution
有很大的貢獻
will definitely get a nobel prize
一定會得到諾貝爾獎
so we will see today
所以我們今天會看到
Getu with a lot of bell awards
有很貝爾獎的格圖
Because of his ELF research and development
因為他ELF的研發上
has a great contribution
有一個很卓越的貢獻
of course i just mentioned
那當然我剛剛提過
Fleming was in 1928
傅蘭明是在1928年
He discovered this phenomenon
他發現了這個現象
That's just that Penisening
那不過那個Penisening
This green plum tree itself is not very stable
這個青梅樹他本身不是很穩定
So there are actually some problems in purification
所以純化上事實上是有一些問題的
Later, because the people under him were
後來由於他下面的人就是
Froory and Chain
Froory跟Chain
Rich and Froory
有錢跟Froory
these two people they are
這兩個人他們就是
is his research
就是他的研究
Browning's research caught his attention
Browning的研究引起他的重視
So they keep putting this
所以他們繼續把這個
This green plum tree, this chemical substance
這個青梅樹這個化學物質
saved successfully
成功的存化出來
And try to figure out how to do production
而且想辦法說怎麼樣做生產
That's because of the contributions of the two of them
那因為他們兩個的貢獻
That's why this green plum tree can produce in large quantities
所以這個青梅樹才能夠大量的生產
Able to provide medical use
能夠提供在醫療上用途
So these three scientists in 1945
所以這三位科學家在1945年的時候
get the nobel prize
得到諾貝爾獎
Look at 1945
你看1945年的時候
when the war was just over
那時候戰爭才剛剛結束的時候
So he got this Nobel Prize in Physiology or Medicine
所以他得到諾貝爾的這個生理學或醫學獎
Where is his contribution?
那他的貢獻在哪邊呢
Froory Discovered Plain City
Froory Discovered Plain City
It is because of the invention of the green plum tree
就是因為青梅樹的發明
Being able to come to this for all kinds of this
能夠來在這個對於各式各樣的這個
Infectious diseases have a therapeutic effect
感染性的疾病上有一個治療的效果
so they got the nobel prize
所以他們得了諾貝爾獎
let me tell you now
那我現在來講一下
its mechanism of action
他的作用機制
Pan Lin's soul
盤林心靈
Just mentioned that if we're looking for a drug today
剛剛提過我們今天如果要找一個藥物
What about the drug?
那這個藥物呢
because it is against bacterial infections
因為它是對細菌感染
It is good if it has no side effects
它如果要好的功能沒有副作用的話
it should be selective
它應該要選擇性
That is to say, the drug
也就是說這個藥物呢
Can't have any effect on humans
不能對人類有任何影響
must not be toxic to humans
不能對人類有毒性
But directly
可是呢直接
And only to sterilize
而且只會去殺菌而已
So we're going to find out
所以我們就要去了解說
How is this bacterium different from a human?
這個細菌跟人有什麼不一樣
that's good
那很好的
Fortunately, that is to say
還好就是說
What about our human cells and bacteria?
我們人類的細胞跟細菌呢
its difference
它的差別
The biggest difference is the bacterial cell B
最大的差別就是細菌的細胞B
So the most important function of elasticity
所以彈性它最主要的作用點
is deeply synthesized in bacterial cells B
是在細菌細胞B的深合成
what about this picture
那這個圖片呢
It's actually a Staphylococcus aureus
事實上是一個金黃色葡萄球菌
that you know
那各位知道
Regardless of the lowly bacteria
不管低等的細菌
to our higher human cells
到高等的我們人類細胞
what about all bacteria or cells
所有的細菌或細胞呢
it will have this cell membrane
它都會有這個細胞膜
Membrane to put the internal environment of this creature
Membrane來把這個生物的內部環境
Isolate from the outside world
跟外環境做個隔離
We say it's a cell membrane
我們說這是個細胞膜
For bacteria
那細菌來講
What about Staphylococcus aureus?
金黃色葡萄球菌呢
he is a bacterium
他是一個細菌
Then he has a thick layer of cell arms on the outside
那他外面有一層厚厚的細胞臂
What is the energy of this cell arm?
那這個細胞臂做什麼的裝能呢
It is a function of structural support
它是個結構支撐的功能
Why
為什麼
Because the bacteria itself has to face the inside and outside of the cell
因為細菌本身他要面臨細胞內外
because he maintains a
因為他維持一個
a physiological
一個生理
That is to say, one of his various substances
就是說他各式各樣的一個物質
He has to maintain a certain concentration
他要維持一個一定的濃度
So he has some osmotic pressure
所以他有一定的滲透壓力
That is to say, the inside and outside of the cell
就是說細胞的內跟外
his
他的
his concentration is different
他的濃度是不同的
So he has a pressure that penetrates him
所以他有一個滲透他的壓力
So if you don't have a strong
所以如果你沒有一個很堅強
supported by a cell arm
支撐的一個細胞臂的話
He can't help that bacteria
那個細菌他沒有辦法
catch directly
直接接住
left thick
剩厚厚
so he bursts again
所以他又會脹破
Moisture keeps coming in and it will burst
水分不斷的進來會脹破
so what
所以呢
Rehearsing the mind today is actually mainly in
今天排練心靈其實主要是在
A synthesis of the cell arm of the main segment
主段這個細胞臂的一個合成
prevent him from building him well
讓他不能把他架構好
What kind of structure is the cell arm of bacteria?
那細菌的細胞臂是怎麼樣的一個架構呢
it's hard for you to say
你把它講難說
Today he is a 3D
今天他是一個3D
A network structure in a three-dimensional space
一個三度空間的一個網狀架構
that he is a
那他是一個
quite complex aggregate molecule
蠻複雜的一個聚合的分子
That is you can say it as saying
也就是說你可以把它講成說
If this is a two-figure
這個是一個二個的圖形的話
If this is a sugar body
如果說這個是一個糖體
a polysaccharide
一個多糖體
a chain of sugar
一個糖體的一鏈
each one is a
每一條都是一個
a polymer of sugar
糖的一個聚合體
What about between each chain?
那這個每一鏈之間呢
must be concatenated
必須要串聯起來
then it will have
那它才會有
Its structure has its strength
它的結構上才有它的強度
that sugar body
那這個糖體
What about the sugar molecules?
這個糖分子之間呢
It must use the ecological key to make a series connection
本身必須要用生態鍵來做一個串聯
that is, as if you were
也就是好像你在
Do this like a past event
這個做一個往事一樣
your
你的
Both vertical and horizontal must be wired
有縱橫都要有線
then contact each other
然後互相去聯繫一樣
that this
那這個
The sugar molecules in the vertical direction have to be connected in series with each other
縱向的這個糖分子本身要互相串聯起來
Need to use ecology
需要用生態
Then this series of steps
那這個串聯的步驟
In fact, in the whole deep synthesis
事實上在整個的深合成裡面的
last step
最後一步
Well, it just so happens that the Chinese New Year is at the last step.
那剛好這蠻年新年就是在最後一步呢
make it impossible to connect
讓它沒有辦法串聯好
So even though it frames this
所以即使它架構好這個
What about sugar polymers?
糖的聚合物呢
But it can't connect well
可是它沒有辦法很好的串聯
so
所以
If you use this barbarian today for New Year's
如果你今天使用的這個蠻年新年的時候
When rehearsing sex, his cell arms are not well connected with each other
排練性的時候他的細胞臂沒有好好的有互相的串聯的話
Bacteria with such a soft structure can easily swell and die
這樣鬆軟的結構細菌還是很容易的脹和就死掉
So this is the main mechanism of rehearsal sex
所以這就是排練性主要作用機制
How did he discover such a phenomenon
他怎麼樣發現這樣子的一個現象
It was actually an unexpected discovery that we ended up coming back
我們最後來回歸實際上是一個很意外的一個發現
But the most important thing is that Dr. Flaming carefully noticed such a problem
可是最主要是Flaming博士人仔細的去注意到這樣子的一個問題
Then add the weather is also a factor
然後加上天氣也是個因素
why?
為什麼呢?
My work is back to September 1928
我事情是歸做到1928年的9月份
At that time, Fleming went on vacation in August
那個時候弗蘭明他8月份的時候出去度假
If you all know Fleming himself, although he was already famous at that time
各位如果知道弗蘭明他本身他雖然他當時就已經很有名
But is he doing the experiment clean?
可是他做實驗事實上是不是很乾淨
Why do you guys take a look
為什麼你各位來看一下
you will see this photo this is not a fake photo
你會看到這個照片這不是做假的照片
You can see that the rows at the back are all the culture names of his bacteria.
你看後面一排一排都是他的細菌的培養名
So after he finished the experiment, he is usually what we say is very annoying to him.
所以他做完實驗他通常就是我們說這個是很拉他的
A researcher just piled it on
一個研究人員就把它堆在上面
so what
所以呢
before he let go
他在放下前
he finished the experiment
他做完實驗
he has painted some on it
他上面已經塗了一些
some golden yellow grapes
一些金黃色葡萄
Just took some experiments on bacterial culture
就拿過一些細菌培養的實驗
finished
做完了
He just put it on the lab table and walked away
他就放在實驗桌就走掉
then come back after a while
然後過了一段時間再回來
so he went out to play in august
所以他八月份出去玩一玩
then come back in september
然後九月份回來
that's just right
那剛好呢
his bacterial culture
他的細菌培養品
Because we usually do bacterial cultures
因為我們通常要做細菌培養品
To avoid the interference of other bacteria
要就是避免其他的細菌的干擾
so usually have a cover
所以通常要有蓋
I didn't expect him to leave before
沒想到他走之前
He did not throw away the experiment
他做完實驗他也沒丟掉
Even the lid is open for some
甚至蓋子有些人都打開了
came back to find out that
回來發現說
what happened
怎麼搞的
opened the lid inside
就有打開了蓋子裡面
Invasion of other species
上面有其他的物種入侵
he noticed
他注意到
if everyone can't see
如果大家不能看到
If students like mine see this situation
像我的學生看到這種情形的話
or me
或是我啦
just to see other pollution
就是看到有其他的污染
he has dropped it
他已經把它丟掉
But he feels very different
可是他覺得特別不一樣
because strange
因為奇怪
He's got a bunch of bacteria all over it.
他上面本來都塗了一大堆細菌
But once this strain is added
可是一旦加了這個菌種以後
Strange that it seems next to
奇怪那個好像旁邊
No bacteria can survive here
這邊的細菌都沒有辦法存活
So he is tantamount to noticing that
所以他等於注意到說
he must be a microbe
他一定是一個微生物
Then this microbe will produce a substance
那這個微生物會產生一個物質
Can have a bactericidal effect
能夠有殺菌的效果
So it's like being here
所以等於是本來在這邊
These are full of bacteria
佔滿了細菌的這些
bacteria taking place
佔滿了位置的細菌
He then backed off
他後來等於是退後了
Because of the existence of this species back off
因為這個物種的存在退後
So he noticed this phenomenon
所以他注意到這個現象
so he thinks
所以他覺得說
He later identified that it was a plum fungus
他後來還鑑定出原來這是一個梅菌
Nomeella because it competes with bacteria
那梅菌因為要跟細菌互相競爭
Because it is covered with soil and has nutrients
因為它上面是土有營養物質
We say this cultivator
我們說這個培養機
Then they have to compete for the training machine
那他們要競爭培養機
So Mei bacteria distinguish some substances
所以梅菌分明一些物質
It's like saying this is my domain
等於說這是我的領域
you can't come
你不能來
So the bacteria are all dead.
所以等於是細菌就全部都死掉
So there must be a chemical substance
所以講說一定有一個化學物質
Chemicals have a bactericidal effect
化學物質具有殺菌的效果
That, of course, later led to his discovery.
那這個當然後來導致他發現的
the Panicia
這個潘尼西菌
that's what i just said
那可是我剛剛講
why climate is a major factor
為什麼氣候是一個主要因素呢
Because of the growth of bacteria he needs
因為細菌的生長他是需要
I also know that it needs to be in a high heat environment
也知道它是要高熱環境之下
So it happens to be the rotating weather in August
所以剛好在8月份的輪流的天氣
Bacteria in this summer environment
細菌的這種夏天的環境
bacteria grow happily
細菌會長得很高興
But it just happened to take turns
可是剛好在輪流那一陣子
It was a cold day for a while
有一陣子是一個很冷的天氣
that cold weather
那冷的天氣
especially cold weather
尤其濕冷的天氣
Because the humidity over there is quite high.
因為輪流那邊濕度是蠻高的
Therefore, it is very conducive to the growth of Mei fungus
所以很有利於梅菌的生長
So there was a summer weather
所以本來有一個夏天的天氣
make this bacteria grow really well
讓這個細菌長得非常好
Just after that there was an invasion of plum fungus
剛好之後有梅菌的入侵
Then there's another cold air
然後又有一段冷空氣
Bacterial growth is inhibited
細菌的生長受到抑制
Then the fungus starts to grow
然後梅菌開始生長出來
So there is such an obvious contrast
所以有這樣一個很明顯的對比
The result of such an obvious contrast
那這樣的明顯的對比的結果
Let Fu Nanmin know
讓浮南民知道了
And he said carefully
而且他特別細心說
this is not rubbish
這個不是垃圾
It's not trash, it's not meant to be thrown away right away
不是垃圾不是要馬上丟掉
Rather, it is an interesting phenomenon
而是說這個現象很有趣
He himself said that instead of thinking about finding out
他本人說他反而去想去找出來說
What kind of a dimensional creature is this?
這個到底是什麼樣的一個維生物
It turned out to be a plum fungus
結果後來發現是一個青梅菌
So we can say that he is a very unexpected
所以我們可以說他是一個很意外的
an event
一個事件
and very lucky
而且是非常幸運
And he is the most important thing to observe carefully
而且他可是他最主要是很仔細的去觀察
get such a discovery
得到這樣的一個發現
Of course Pan Senji
那潘森基他當然
we just talked
我們剛剛講過
There will be a Jibang in the back
後面的會有一個吉榜
It is Foreign and Chains
就是Foreign and Chains
These two he began to explain
這兩位他開始了解說
Oh, found this phenomenon
喔 發現這個現象
He removed the bill of materials
他把物質單移出來
Then prove that this is green plum tree
然後證明說這個是青梅樹
what about the problem
那問題呢
What if he can sterilize
他怎麼樣如果能夠殺菌
He can certainly deal with bacterial infections
他當然可以對付細菌的感染
The question is how to apply it to people
問題是怎麼樣來應用在人身上
Because by then
因為到當時啊
Bacterial infection is a
細菌的感染是一個
basically a testimonial
基本上是一個不知之證
It's kind of like we got HIV now
就有點像我們現在碰到HIV
AIDS is the same as encountering this Cancer
AIDS或是碰到這個Cancer一樣
basically unknown evidence
基本上是不知之證
So at that time there was a big
所以呢那個時候就有被很大
an effort is to say how
一個努力就是說怎麼樣
to mass produce it
來把它做大量生產
Then let me tell you that the data is
那我跟你講那數據就是
He discovered in 1928
他1928年發現
But by 1942
可是到1942年的時候
All over the United States and the entire Pensenkey's
全美國整個潘森基的
The total output can only be one dead patient
整個總產量只能一死個病人而已
Because it cannot be mass-produced
因為那個送沒辦法大量生產
because i just said
因為我剛剛講過
Panlin Xinyu itself has many problems.
盤林心育本身它有很多問題就是
The first one is unstable, how do you produce it
第一個它不穩你怎麼樣生產
the second is
第二個就是
And another question is that
而且另外一個問題就是說
What about its absorption in the body?
它在人體的吸收呢
The most original version of Panlin Xinyu is
最原始版本的盤林心育是
Not easily absorbed in the body
在人體裡面不容易吸收
Probably only two to three two percent can be absorbed
大概只能二三個百分之二被吸收
So most of it is drained
所以大部分都排掉
equal to if you give it
等於是如果你給它
For example, eating a ground
比如說吃了一個ground
A word of Pan Lin's heart
一個盤林心育的話
About two or three hundred milligrams will go away
大概有兩三百毫克會跑掉
So, when it was time to do Pan Lin Xin Yu
那所以呢當時要去做盤林心育的時候呢
Patient's urine shadow it goes to recycling
病人的尿影它去回收
because it passes into the urine
因為它排到尿裡面
Look at Taiwan's storage and recycling
看台灣存化回收
If not, the whole
不能的話會整個
Because you have 70% to 80% of Pan Lin Xinyu wasted
因為你有七八十%的盤林心育浪費掉
this is a serious problem
這是嚴重的問題
So at that time
所以當時呢
And it stays in the body for a short time
而且呢它在體內的停留時間不久
So it's all downsides of the drug
所以這都是藥物的缺點
So fortunately Pan Lin Xinyu discovered it by accident
所以還好盤林心育是意外發現
From a modern perspective
如果是現代的眼光的話
This Pan Lin Xinyu must be abandoned
這個盤林心育一定是被捨棄掉
because it doesn't meet our requirements
因為它不符合我們的要求
it has a low absorption rate
它吸收率低
Then and easily in the body
然後而且很容易在體內
only three or four hours but not good
只有三四個小時 但不好
Then you need to pay attention
那你還要各位注意到
This Fulhamming he is in England
這個Fulhamming他是在英國
so that england is at war
所以那個英國在戰爭
And the UK especially rounds every day
而且英國尤其是輪跟每天
to the German bombing
就到德軍的轟炸
Basically, the country will send people
基本上這個國要派人
So they went to talk to the British government
所以當時他們去跟英國政府講說
Can you come to produce panxing
可不可以來生產盤興
Because we don't have the strength
因為我們沒有這個力氣
And at that time there was still a doubt that
而且當時還有個疑虛就是說
At that time, the three recommended
當時這三位推薦家裡面
That seems to be Frolly he claims
那個好像是Frolly他主張說
We're going to take this pattern
我們要把這個pattern
Because this will definitely sell well in the future
因為這個以後一定是可以大賣
Fortunately, Fulhamming and Chain objected
那可是還好是Fulhamming跟Chain他反對
Said this is if it can be used like this
說這個是如果這樣子可以用
make a significant contribution to human well-being
對人的福祉有重大的貢獻
So they refuse to pattern
所以他們拒絕去pattern
so what
那所以呢
Fulhamming he is generous
Fulhamming他很慷慨
He sent the county chief to people everywhere.
他就到處把那個郡總寄給人家
See if it can be applied
看能不能應用
So they just have to go to America to find
所以他們只要跑到美國來尋求
so America
所以美國呢
They came across this like a gift from the sky
他們碰到這個好像是天上掉下來的禮物
they are happy
他們很高興
So the various plans in it
所以就其中各式各樣的計畫
to find a good county chief
去找尋好的郡總
So they later in E-NOR
所以他們後來在E-NOR
likely that
很可能那個
Wang Furen at the market in Enoi
王富人在Enoi的市場上
find a rotten cantaloupe
找到一個爛掉的哈密瓜
The green plum mushrooms on the rotten cantaloupe
這爛掉哈密瓜上面的青梅菇
Proven to be one of the best strains
證明是一個最好的菌種
Because the output is very high
因為產量非常高
and
而且
Back then Midwest farming was fresh
那時候美國中西部農業很新鮮
so they later found out
所以他們後來發現
because a lot of corn is grown in the Midwest
因為中西部種很多玉米
It turns out they found that the corn
結果他們發現要把玉米
There will be a lot of emissions in the province of turning into cornmeal
變成玉米粉這個爬省裡面會排放很多
this boiling water
這個沸水
This boiling water is used
這個沸水用來
Do this Plum Fermentation
做這個青梅菌的發酵
its yield is very very good
它的產率非常非常的好
so
所以
one like this
當時這樣子的一個
As a result of optimization, its yield is the original
最佳化的結果它的產率是原先
Disk Venus found more than 100,000 times
盤金星發現的10萬倍以上
So by 1942, the entire U.S. production could only be used by 10 patients
所以呢到了1942年的時候整個美國產量只能供10個病人使用
By 1943
到了1943年的時候
that time
那個時候
they can be mass produced
他們可以大量生產
so until
所以一直到
I'll talk about the next one first
我先講下面一個
So until 1944
所以一直到了1944年的時候呢
what about them at that time
他們那個時候呢
can already know
可以已經可以知道
2.3 million doses of this
230萬劑的這個
this dose
這個劑量
So there's enough for over 2 million doses
所以有足夠200多萬劑
You can live until 1942 with only 10 patients available
你可以住到1942年只有10個病人可以用
So it is now possible to produce doses up to 230
所以現在已經可以生產到230的劑量
So everyone came to the United States
所以大家後來美國
When the whole Confederates landed from France
整個同盟國他們從法國弄完地登陸的時候
heavy casualties
有很大的傷亡
So they can heal the casualty with resistance
所以他們可以用抗亂度來醫療這個傷亡
Well, this is already known to everyone
那這個是已經大家知道就是說
They have estimated that there is Pandey's influence
他們有估計就是說有潘迪的影響
So what about Confederate soldiers?
所以同盟國的士兵呢
His casualty rate has been reduced by 12 to 15 percent
他的這個傷亡率降低了12到15%
then you'll see this is changing the history of war
那你會看到這是改變戰爭的歷史
Because at this time in Germany they only used Huang Ah Nei's medicine Pontosio
因為這時候德國他們只有用到黃阿內的藥Pontosio
That's the Confederates already have Pandy Sydney.
那可是同盟國這邊已經有潘迪悉尼
And there are millions of doses
而且有好幾百萬的劑量
So the difference between the two sides is
所以兩邊差了就
The soldiers of the German side were injured
德國那邊的人的軍人受傷了
Probably depends on how good his immune system is.
大概要看他的免疫系統的好壞
But here you have antibiotics to treat
可是這邊的話你就有抗生素可以來治療
So at that time there was a poster
所以那個時候有個海報
You see three genera pandy sydney
你看三屬潘迪悉尼
thought there was come home
以為有come home
because he was hurt
因為他受傷了
But because of proper handling, he will still return to the plane.
可是因為有適當的處理他還是會回機
The other one is a very famous experiment in 193
來另外這個呢是在193年來一個很著名的實驗
Then everyone see this is a little girl
那各位看到這是一個小女孩
You see she was healed in the end
你看最後她被治好了
it's a normal little girl
這是正常的小女孩
But at the beginning, there was a serious sense of narrative
可是一開始的時候有嚴重的敘述感
Look at him, this, this, this eye clip is next to his eye
你看他這個這個這個眼夾跟他眼旁邊
This wound is almost festering badly.
這個傷口都幾乎很嚴重的潰爛
You see, this is after adding Penning psychology
你看這個是加了潘寧心理以後
his medical effects
他的醫療效果
You will see the wound gradually shrink
你會看到傷口逐漸的縮小
Then this side has already started to the whole domain now
然後這邊已經開始到現在全域了
Then there is still some swelling here basically.
然後這邊呢基本上還是有一些腫脹
But basically the wound has gradually disappeared.
可是基本上傷口已經要逐漸消失了
So you basically end up late
所以你基本上到最後後期
you can barely see the wound
你基本上看不到傷口
So this is a very famous experiment
所以這是一個很很著名的實驗
It's like adding Pan Ning's psychology to the body
等於說讓潘寧心理加人體上
He was indeed able to deal with this delicate infection
他的確確能夠去去對付這個細心的感染
that is very famous
那是非常有名
Then let's see the picture just above
那我們來看到剛剛上面的圖
This is just at that time one by one
這是剛剛當時一個一個
You see, everyone knows that this is Xiao Wangsun?
你看這個是大家知道是蕭王孫嗎
It's an ad from 1944
是1944年的一個廣告
you look like one by one
你看做起來像是一個一個
Just do it on this oil drum
就是在這個油桶上做
look
你看
Pandin Faith Cure Gonorrhea This is a disease
潘丁信念Cure Gonorrhea 這是臨病
you see in 4 hours
你看 in 4 hours
So you see this number is very similar to now
所以你看這個數與現在很像
This drug can release a certain disease within 4 hours
這個藥可以釋藥某個病在4小時之內
然後 see your doctor today
然後 see your doctor today
please see a doctor today
請今天就去看醫生
so you see this time
所以你看到這個時候
Because it used to be like this, of course it is a sexual disease
因為以前像這個當然臨病是個性病
I thought it was terminal illness
當時都認為這是個絕症
You see pandin believe in invention he will tell you
你看潘丁信念發明他會告訴你說
4 hours to complete the doctor
4個小時就可以全醫
So get a doctor today
所以今天趕快找醫生吧
this is his ad
這是他的廣告
Well, I just mentioned that on case 24
好了那我剛剛提過在24個案上
especially at some point
尤其在某期的時候
He has been able to produce like this because of Panding belief
他因為潘丁信念已經可以這樣生產
And then and can be millions of doses
然後而且可以上上百萬劑
So the successful application in this battlefield
所以成功的應用在這個這個戰場上
and save many lives
然後拯救很多人的生命
And at the same time, he also drove the pharmaceutical industry in the United States
然後同時他也帶動了美國的醫藥工業
because at the beginning it was before 24 cases
因為當時一開始在24個案之前
actually like merc
事實上像merc
he said it was that
他說是那個
Originally, the company was actually a small company.
本來公司其實都是小公司
But because at this time the United States they
可是因為這時候美國他們
Put a lot of manpower and material resources on the arms industry
把大量人力物力的頭量在軍火工業上
Because these guns, bullets, planes, and ships are all used in war
因為這些槍 子彈 飛機 船都要應用在戰爭上
because they are in the pharmaceutical industry
因為他們就頭上在醫藥工業
Because it takes a lot of rehearsal hearts to save military casualties
因為要生產大量的排練心靈來拯救軍人的傷亡
So at this time after the war they talked about
所以這個時候在戰後他們就講說
Hey, rehearsing the mind has such a drill
欸 排練心靈有這麼有鑽頭
yes we can learn from success stories
是我們可以從成功故事裡面
Let's go find other medicines
我們去找其他的藥物分
It also has antiseptic properties
他也有殺菌的性質
So in our 50s, 60s, really into the 70s
所以在我們的50年代、60年代、真正到70年代
In the past twenty or thirty years
這二、三十年間
They searched for all kinds of bacteria from all over the world
他們就從全世界各地去找各式各樣的菌種
including bacteria,
包括細菌、美菌
Because this, for example, bacteria and bacteria are living with each other
因為這個比如說細菌和細菌之間彼此在生存
That is to say, the fire is in the same environment
就是說火在同一個環境裡面
They will naturally overcome each other
他們自然而然就會互相相剋
then we saw
那當時我們看到
Why can the United States bacteria
美菌為什麼可以
It is the same reason why this beautiful bacteria can be sterilized
這個美菌怎麼可以殺菌也是一樣的道理
they survive
他們為了要生存
They'll have this chemical power for each other
他們就會彼此有這種化學物質的靈力
so what
所以呢
this is only
這只是
Just to tell you a few examples
只是跟各位講其中幾個範例
For example, the Panlin Xinlin we saw just now
比如說剛剛我們看到的盤林信林
it is a four five membered ring
它是一個四五元環
Then this tetrahexacyclic ring is called cephalosporin
那這個四六環我們稱為頭包菌素
Its mechanism of action is basically the same as that of Panlin Xinlin
它的作用的機制基本上是跟盤林信林是一樣
But let me tell you that Panlin Xinlin has many, many problems.
不過我跟大家講盤林信林有很多很多問題
Let's say it's one person dealing with Gram-positive bacteria
比如說它是一個人對付格蘭式陽性菌
That Pan Lin Xin Lin it has some instability issues
那盤林信林它有一些不穩定的問題
Then this avatar
那這個像頭包素
Cebas Corin
Cebas Corin
this kind of hair
就是這一類的發物
It's actually what we call the Wise Bed
它事實上我們說是Wise Bed床
So if you say you have a cold today
所以今天如果說你感冒
or some infection
或是有一些感染的話
The doctor had an upper respiratory infection
醫生有一次上呼吸道反染
Doctors usually give you a standard prescription
醫生通常都會給你一個標準的一個處方
Cebaloxin
就是Cebaloxin
this class of drugs
這一類的藥物
That other class
那另外類
For example, just said
比如說剛剛講過
This is Panlin Xinlin drugs
這就是盤林信林類的藥物
but we'll talk later
可是我們等一下會講
It has the problem of bacteria itself and some resistance
它有細菌本身也會有一些抗藥性的問題
So it targets the drug resistance problem
那所以它針對抗藥性問題
Lin Xinlin
它把這盤林信林
do some chemical modification on it
把它做一些化學修飾
So this is Panlin Xinlin, which mainly targets drug resistance.
所以這個是主要最針對抗藥性的盤林信林
and these other drugs
那還有其他這些藥物
For example like
比如說像
carouselomine just mentioned
剛剛講的carouselomine
Just started
剛開始
Didn't I have a prescription room at first?
我剛開始不是有處方間嗎
The doctor has prescribed this carouselomine
醫生有開這carouselomine
In addition there is this
另外還有這個
tetracycline
四環素
are some commonly used
都是一些常用
like in eye ointment
比如說在眼藥膏裡面
Tetracyclines are often present
常常都有四環素的存在
These are after the war
這些都是在戰後
constant search
不斷的搜尋
Different strains from around the world
世界各地的不同的菌種
came to find this compound
來找到了這個化合物
ok we are done now
好 那我們現在講完了
after antibiotics
抗生素之後呢
we now run into this
我們現在碰到這個
Problems we are currently experiencing
我們目前碰到的問題
Because
因為在
Although I just said
雖然我剛剛講過
after the second year
在二次的那一年以後
twenty or thirty years
二三十年間
Although our scientists found
雖然我們科學家找到了
There are dozens of different antibiotics
有幾十種不同的抗生素
that looks like
那看起來
This war seems to be human
這個戰爭好像是人類
the upper hand
上風
Absolutely not
完全沒有
we only want certain drugs
我們只要某一些藥物
if it falls
掉下去的話
bacteria will die
細菌就會死掉
Not really
不盡然
because I just told you
因為我剛剛跟各位講
Currently encountering problem B
目前碰到問題B
The problem is even bigger in this case
這案的時候問題還更大
bacteria
就是我們目前很可能細菌
we'll find some superbugs
我們會找到一些超級細菌
This bacterium will kill all current resistant cases
這個細菌會對目前所有的抗案數
will produce resistance
會產生抵抗的作用
In fact, this problem existed very early
事實上這個問題很早就存在
That is, when rehearsing for a psychologist to use
就是說當時在排練心理醫師使用的時候
There is a problem of drug resistance when used in humans
用在人身上就有抗藥性的問題
Just because there are new drug molecules being invented all the time
只是因為有不斷的有新的藥物分子發明
So this question is ignored
所以這個問題是被忽視的
words here
這邊的話
What strategies do bacteria have?
細菌到底有什麼策略
Will there be such a good antimicrobial strategy?
會有這麼好的抗藥菌的策略呢
Basically my side is just talking about two or three different ways
基本上我這邊只是講了兩三個不同的方式
That is to say, the bacteria have a way
就是說細菌它有一種方式
is that it uses a Lactamase
就是它用一個Lactamase
That is to say, it is a decomposing enzyme
也就是說它是一個分解酶
Which means you use rehearsal psychomedicine
也就是說你用排練心理醫藥物
It can use it to produce a special enzyme
它可以用它生產特殊的一個酵素
Can break down your drug molecules
可以把你的藥物分子給分解
So it even if the drug molecule
所以它就即使這個藥物分子
can go inside its bacteria to sterilize
能夠到它細菌裡面去殺菌
but it can tear you apart
可是它可以把你分解掉
make you useless
讓你沒有作用
another one he can
另外一個他可以的
He doesn't need to disassemble
他不用分解
He just takes your drug molecule
他只是把你的藥物分子
just make it a decoration
只是把它做一個修飾
Originally this molecule of yours
本來你的這個分子
so that he can continue
就要他可以再繼續
a molecule at a certain position
某一個位置的一個分子
because it doesn't work anymore
因為修飾以後再也沒有作用
he can also bacteria
他也可以細菌
He produces something like a helping
他會產生一些類似幫補的東西
bring your stuff in
把你的東西一進來
just hit it outside
就把它打到外面去
Hit it outside as soon as you come in
一進來就把它打到外面去
so your meds never work
所以你的藥物永遠沒有辦法
into the bacteria
進到這個細菌的裡面
so he has all sorts of different strategies
所以他有各式各樣不同的策略
molecules to fight our drugs
來對抗我們這些藥物的分子
What kind of strategy is there?
那還有什麼樣的策略呢
That is to say, bacteria basically
就是說細菌基本上
It has many disadvantages than us
它比我們人有很多缺點
has many advantages
有很多的優點
why
為什麼呢
From birth until our twenties
我們人從出生一直到二十幾歲
We often get married and have children
我們常常會有結婚生小
The bacteria I just talked about
那細菌我剛剛講過
he grows very fast
他長得非常快
In twenty minutes he is a generation
二十分鐘他就一個世代
start splitting
就開始分裂
that and he a lot
那而且他很多
Usually like when you get a bacterial infection
通常比如說你得到細菌感染的時候
Your body has a population of millions of bacteria
你身體有上百萬個細菌的數量
and he's easy
而且他很容易過
So he has mutations of all kinds
所以他有突變各式各樣不同的
aftermath
的後患
sure as long as
肯定是只要
Let's say you have millions of different mutants
比如說你有上百萬個不同的突變種的話
As long as one can resist antibiotics
只要一個能夠對抗抗生素的話
he survived
他就存活下來
Let me give you a practical statistical example
那我這邊來舉一個實際的一個統計的例子
come talk to you
來跟各位講
This is revealed from a book
這是從一本書上揭露下來的
that is to say today
就是說今天就是說
A patient enters for whatever reason
一個病人進到不管是什麼原因
he went into the hospital
他進到醫院裡面去
what about this time
那這個時候呢
We have a few dorms here
我們這邊有幾個宿裡面
Let me give you a little explanation
跟各位稍微做說明
If it is a MS here
這邊如果說是一個MS的話
He said that for this Message in Sensitive
他說對於這個Message in Sensitive
That means he's a drug for you
就是說他是對你的藥物
can be sensitive
可以有有有有感應的
It means that the medicine you are taking is effective
就是你用的藥物是可以有效的
What if R
如果是R的話呢
It is Message in Resistant
就是Message in Resistant
That is, he is a drug-resistant strain
就是他是抗藥性的一個菌種
That means after entering the hospital
那等於說進了醫院以後
at this time
這個時候
This your length is 164 square
這個你的身長164方
about a million bacteria
大概上百萬個細菌
Of course you, you, after you add the medicine
那當然你你你加了藥以後
like this C8 week tone
像這個C8周音
This is one of the cephalospoins we just talked about
這個是我們剛剛講頭包菌素的其中一種
After adding an anti-trace element
多於加了一個抗痕素以後
you fight bacterial infections
你對抗細菌感染
On the second day, most normal people and 90% of patients
那第二天大部分正常人90%的病人
After two days of anti-trace treatment, you should be able to go home
兩天的抗痕素的處理之後應該就可以回家了
But if this patient
可是如果因這個病人
he has other problems
他還有其他方面的問題
Or he's not fully healed
或是他的還沒有完全康復
he has to be taken inside the hospital
他必須帶在醫院裡面
So at this time they also went to study
所以這個時候他們也去研究
The bacteria in this patient are starting to change.
這病人身上的菌種開始有變化
why? just started you are
為什麼?剛剛開始你是
Sensitive to this drug
對於這個藥是有感應的
can be cured
是可以被治癒的
At the beginning, if you are drug-resistant, MRSA
開始你有抗藥性的就MRSA
if resistant
如果有抗藥性
The doctor said it's okay if it's resistant
醫生說如果抗藥性沒關係
I use other drugs
我用其他的藥物來講
Several different drugs may be added
可以有加幾種不同的藥物
After adding it to a week later
加了以後到一個禮拜以後
If you can heal and go home, you'll be fine.
如果能夠治癒回家就沒事
If the body is still very bad
如果身體還是很不好的時候
At this time you will see all the strains
這個時候你會看到所有的菌種
Originally, only a small number of bacterial strains here were resistant to antibiotics.
本來這邊大概只有少數的菌種有抗藥性
Here are all the strains are so-called MR
這邊是所有的菌種都是所謂的MR
Staphylococcus aureus
抗藥性的一個金王式葡萄球菌
And the trees that spawned were originally from 1,000,000
而且菌種的樹木本來是從100萬
Now change to 1000
現在變1000個
like trees come back again
像樹木又恢復了
At this time, if you are not yet valid
那這個時候如果你還沒有效的
Even if you still have to lie in the hospital
就是還必須躺在醫院的時候
this time you will use this
這個時候你就要用這個
venomoxin we passed
我們通過的venomoxin
Basically the last line of defense
基本上最後一道防線了
Then if it works at this time, it works
那這個時候如果有效就有效
if not valid
如果沒有效的時候
You have to stay in the patient for 20 days
你還要待在病人20天以後
you at this time the drug
你這個時候這個藥物
Basically this bacteria is a superbug
基本上這個細菌是超級細菌
so of course we
所以我們這樣當然
I don't think there will be any problems here
在場各位我想不會有任何的問題
that is to say
就是說這些
why some people end up
為什麼有一些人為什麼會到最後
because some of the people he was very sick
因為有一些他病得很重的人
or he's clearly vulnerable
或是他明顯很脆弱
chemotherapy patients
化療的病人
or very elderly patients
或是說年紀非常大的病人
This one of his is clearly already fragile
他的這個明顯已經很脆弱
So if you stay in the hospital for a long time at this time
所以這個時候如果長期在醫院裡面
Because the hospital you have been giving drugs
因為醫院你一直不斷的給藥物
Those antioxidants are constantly mutated
那一斷的給這些抗氧素有突變
have that
有那個
Opportunity to choose
選擇的機會
so what
所以呢
Finally, if you have been lying on the ice sheet,
最後如果一直躺在冰原的話
finally maybe basically
最後可能基本上
All antibiotics are ineffective
所有的抗肮素都沒有效
this is a very dire situation
這是一個非常可怕的情況
the other one
那另外一個
when I introduce you
跟各位來介紹的時候
This is also a statistical figure
這也是一個統計上的數字
we can talk about this
我們可以講說這個
anticorrosion
這個跟抗肮素
Continuing the fight against this infection
繼續的這個感染的對抗
do not stop
不中止
why
為什麼呢
Because when we usually take antibiotics
因為我們通常吃抗肮素的時候
Usually we are very suspicious
通常我們很疑神
For example, today we
比如說我們今天
doctor tell you
醫生跟你講說
You have an infection and you need antibiotics
你感染了你要吃抗肮素
you have to eat for a week
你要吃一個禮拜
most people say
大部分人說
I'll be fine in two or three days
我兩三天好了
to help him with the refrigerator
要幫他冰箱
next time
下一次
It can also be used when the infection is perfect
完美感染的時候還可以用
No need to go to the doctor twice
不用去看兩次醫生
too wasteful
太浪費
that or
那或者說
sometimes you have side effects
有時候你有副作用
When taking antibiotics
一吃抗肮素的時候
because you put your gut
因為你把你腸道的
All intentions killed him
有意境都把他殺死了
you made him have diarrhea
你害得他拉肚子
you develop other symptoms
你發育有其他的症狀
you are a doctor
你當醫生
Then put the medicine back and stop
那就把藥加回停一下
It turned out
結果好了
have forgotten
有忘掉
then it is not normal to use
那就不正常使用
that actually increases the bacteria
那事實上就會增加細菌
chance of survival
生存的機會
In addition, generally we are on the feed of overtime acceleration
另外一般我們在加勤加速的飼料上
Because sometimes you want high-density farming
因為有的時候你要高密度的養殖
For example, you are in this pigsty
比如說你在這個豬圈裡面
Rarely able to raise 100 pigs
很少能養100頭豬
But for high yield
可是為了要產量高
Suddenly raised 300 pigs
突然就養300頭豬
So many creatures together can also get sick
那麼多的生物在一起也會生病
So some antibiotics are added to the feed
所以在飼料裡面加了一些抗生素
it will not have bacterial infection
它就不會有細菌感染
This is the result of the actual same order
這個是實際同階的結果
The gray is darker than this bully
灰色比較顏色比較深的這個霸
It is the result of our use of cephalosporin
是說我們使用頭豹菌素的結果
The white words are found we say drug resistance
那白色的話是發現我們說抗藥性
golden cephalopod antibiotic resistant bacteria
金黃色頭豹菌性抗藥性的細菌
You can see that when we increase the amount of antibiotics
你可以看到我們如果提高抗生素的用量的時候
You can see that after a year or two
你可以看到隔一兩年以後
resistant bacteria
抗藥性的細菌
It will also increase in number
它的數量也會跟著增加
In other words, if you increase the amount of antibiotics used,
也就是說你增加抗生素的使用量的話
As a result, you have an increased chance of finding resistance
結果你發現抗藥性的機會有增加
Then you put the amount of antibiotic
然後你把抗生素的用量
lower slowly
慢慢降低
as a result you see
結果你看到
Antibiotic bacteria are also slowly declining
抗生素的細菌也慢慢下降
And you rise to he rises to
而你又升到他又升到
For example, this is something like
比如說這個是有點像是
half water
半水的
Say you take antibiotics
比如說你用抗生素
Naturally there is Wu Wu's Xiangke
自然就有了烏烏的相克
Bacteria will find ways to get at you
細菌就會方式來對付你
So the bacteria that can fight you will also increase with him
所以能夠對抗你的細菌也會跟他增加
It's half water
就是半水
So this life will never end
所以這種生是永遠不會結束的
This lets you understand
這讓各位來了解
Okay, I'm done thinking about this antibiotic.
好了那想完了這個抗生素
we pick up now
我們現在接起來
to this diet pill
到這個減肥藥
what about diet pills
減肥藥呢
our this
我們這個
This we call Anti-Obsert
這我們叫Anti-Obsert
Obsert actually means fat
Obsert其實是肥胖的意思
that is
就是說
i just said
我剛剛講過
I mean we have obesity
我就是說我們有肥胖
Of course it doesn't pose any threat to us
當然不會對我們身邊有什麼任何威脅
Of course everyone wants to say
當然大家都想說
There is no TV in this day and age
在這個時代都沒電視
everyone says
大家都說
I won't tell you how skinny this girl is
不會講說這個女生有多瘦
Multiple aiming bars
多瞄條
how fat is this girl
這個女生有多胖
How big is her size
她的Size有多大
impossible
不可能這樣
So generally speaking, if you carry a little
所以一般來講說如果你稍微扛一下
If you can't do it with diet and exercise
如果你沒有辦法藉由飲食跟運動的話
Then we have to use drugs
那就只好借助藥物
General weight-loss drugs probably cannot escape from these three functions
一般的減肥藥大概脫離不了這三種作用
This drug directly reduces your appetite
這個藥物直接就降低你的食慾
Make you not want to eat and make you feel full all the time
讓你不想吃 讓你覺得總是覺得好飽
Otherwise it's altering your rookie's ability to metabolize
不然就是改變你新人代謝的能力
It means to let you, a newcomer, metabolize
就是說讓你這個新人代謝
It was originally you, for example, after we are middle-aged
就是本來你比如說一般我們上了中年以後
If the newcomer's metabolism becomes low
如果說新人代謝變低
It is very likely that after eating, everything will be easily tired in the body.
很可能就吃下去東西都容易累在體內
Increase the rate of your newcomer's metabolism
增加你的新人代謝的速率
or what you ate today
或是說今天你吃下去的東西
If you don't absorb it, you won't let it out
不讓你吸收就不讓你排掉
so change your appetite
所以就是改變你的食慾
Otherwise it is to increase the rate of your newcomer's metabolism
不然就是增強你的新人代謝的速率
Otherwise, what you eat will not be absorbed
不然就是讓你吃下去的東西不能吸收
these three
就是這三種
so we say diet pills
所以我們說減肥藥
Also known as We lost drop
也稱為叫We lost drop
just let you eat
就是讓你吃了東西
sorry, drugs that make you lose weight
對不起 讓你的體重能夠降低的藥物
Usually, you diet pills
通常啦,你這些減肥藥
There will be instructions on it that say
它上面都會有說明就是說
I hope you can keep your diet balanced and exercise
希望你能夠保持你的飲食上的均衡跟運動
he knows hope
他懂是希望
If your medicine is no joke, don't sue him
你藥物如果沒笑話,不要來告他
Because do you have to pay attention to diet?
因為你到底有沒有飲食上要注意
Are you really exercising?
你到底有沒有真的在運動
If you don't do it, you can't sue him if he can do it
如果你沒有做之後,他做得到你不能去告他
There are currently two drugs
那目前有兩種藥物
a Zenicle
一個稱為Zenicle
That one is called Redactyl
那一個叫Redactyl
Then we call it screw fairy in Chinese
那我們中文稱為螺絲仙
then to make you cool
然後是讓你酷
Then there's Redactyl's falling beauty
然後是Redactyl的落美
that you know
那各位知道
The business of our drug is actually the same as the general one
我們這個藥物的business,事實上跟一般都是一樣
why?
為什麼呢?
Look at this Zenicle
你看這個Zenicle
It's called screw fairy
它叫螺絲仙
But our troublesome Laninq in Taiwan
可是我們台灣麻煩的Laninq
Because of the name Zenicle
因為Zenicle這個名稱
You see it makes you cool, because it's cool to lose weight
你看讓你酷,因為瘦下來就會很酷了
so what
所以呢
So I think the name of our Taiwan class
所以我覺得我們台灣班的名
Because this term is only used in Taiwan
因為這個名詞只有在台灣地區使用
If you are in the general South China area, you still use the screw fairy
你如果在一般的華南地區,還是用螺絲仙
that in addition
那另外
Luo Meiting
叫落美亭
You have to speak Taiwanese, Luo Weiting
你要講台語喔 羅維廷
If you eat your weight, you will lose weight
吃了體重會羅維廷
This English is also very good
這英文也取得很好
Cause R-E-D-U-O-R-E-D-U-O
因為R-E-D-U-O-R-E-D-U-O
It means lowering
就是降低的意思
R-E-D-U-O-R-E-D-U-O
R-E-D-U-O-R-E-D-U-O
So the naming is very interesting
所以這個命名是很有趣的
This is very knowledgeable
這個是很有學問的
Then let's talk about these two drugs to explain to you
那我們就講這兩項藥物來跟各位來說明
this Rochester
這個羅氏仙
Zenico, as I just mentioned, is a photo of Miku
Zenico我剛剛講到是照上米庫
What about the drug?
那這個藥物呢
Rosh
是由羅氏藥廠Rosh
In most countries, he will do business and sales
在大部分國家就由他來做經營銷售
what about this drug
那這個藥物怎麼樣
found out
發現呢
they were in
當時他們是在
As I said just now, it means that the material is collected from nature.
我剛剛講過也是說是在自然界取材
So he's in this kind of coal smelter
所以他在這一種煉煤具裡面
Deposited Drugs
去存化到的藥物
Then you will see that this is the stored medicine
那你會看到這個是存化到的藥物
Then this is the main ingredient of our later Zenico
那這個是我們後來Zenico主要成分
Then you'll see that the complete difference is
那你會看到它的完全差別是
This looks like it has two swords on it
這看上上面有雙劍
But generally speaking, this kind of double sword
不過一般來講這種雙劍的話
will be more unstable
會比較不穩定
So they decided he reduced it to a saturated carbon chain
所以他們決定他把它還原成為一種飽和的碳鏈
so this is later
所以這是後來
Later, the more stable version is used in this Zeniko
後來比較穩定的版本是用在這個Zeniko裡面
The main cost of this screw room
那這個螺絲間的主要的成本
what is it for
是要做什麼用
How does it work?
它的作用機在怎麼樣呢
What they found was against us in Congyizang
他們發現是在對抗我們在從宜藏
The Lipase secreted by Chris Yizang
Chris宜藏裡面分泌的這個Lipase
Is it the breakdown of fat?
就是脂肪的分解沒
In other words, we usually eat mushrooms in the food
也就是說我們通常吃菌的食物裡面
start to be broken down in the digestive tract
在消化道要開始被分解
What if it's fat
如果是脂肪的時候呢
what about this time
這個時候呢
Usually need this lipolysis does not work
通常需要這個脂肪分解沒作用
It becomes small molecules of fat that will be absorbed by Xiaochang
它變成小分子的脂肪才會被小長所吸收
What if at this time
如果這個時候呢
you added drugs
你加了藥物
Can put this Lipase
能夠把這個Lipase
Suppress this N-RAN
把這個N-RAN給抑制住
This N-RAN has no way to work
這個N-RAN沒有辦法作用
So you'll find that says
所以你會發現說
the fat you eat
你吃下去的脂肪
it won't be broken down
它不會被分解
will not be absorbed
不會被吸收
will be drained
會被排掉
so what are its side effects
所以它的副作用是什麼呢
just drain oil
就是會排油
sorry press too fast
對不起 按太快了
will drain oil
會排油
So the main side effect of this screw room
所以這個螺絲間的最主要的副作用
everybody knows
大家都知道
if you have eaten
如果你有吃過的話
you will know say
你會知道說
it causes disturbances in your intestines
它會造成你大小腸上的擾動
Then to the part that will let you pull the oil out
然後到部分會讓你拉出油出來
Then I have friends who have eaten Ross Union
那我有朋友吃過羅斯聯
I haven't eaten
我沒有吃過啦
Although my weight is not very standard
雖然我體重不是很標準
but that is to say
不過就是說
I've heard that he sometimes
我聽過就是他有時候
It's just that you have to eat too normally
就是你要吃得太正常的
Just follow the kitchen to eat
就是按照廚房來吃的話
you won't be able to get in
你會進不住
will run up your pants
會跑到你的褲子上面去
Because that oil is still too fast
因為那個油是還太快
because usually we say sorry
因為一般我們說對不起
I'm talking nasty
我講的比較噁心
Let's defecate is going piece by piece
讓我們的排便是要一塊一塊
that will be slower
那會比較慢慢來
But because it was oily at that time
可是因為那時候有油狀
So these substances will be discharged very smoothly
所以這些物質會排得非常順暢
so sometimes you don't
所以有時候你都沒
No it's a side effect of a Manzao
不是這個是個滿早人的副作用
But it's okay
不過還好
That's because compared to the next words
那因為比起下一個的話
he is very good
他就好很
Rowe Hall
這羅維廳
What about the Rowe Hall?
那這個羅維廳呢
it's mostly about being aware of your appetite
它這主要是意識你的食慾
Then this problem will be more
那這個問題會比較多
why
為什麼呢
Because it is mainly to target your
因為它主要的是去針對你的這個
Because there are some hormones in our body
因為我們身體裡面有一些荷爾蒙
normal here
正常這邊的話
The reaction is really
反應實在是
For example, our kidney adenoids
譬如說我們的腎臟腺素
and this
還有這個
Sterotonic it turns golden amine
Sterotonic它翻成金色胺
Or Dopamine Dopaamine
或是Dopamine都Dopa胺
These things are neurotransmitters
這些東西是神經傳導物質
that's in the body
那在身體裡面
Its quantity is strictly controlled
它的量是要被嚴格控制的
then these should
那這些要
these are
這些都
The main function of this Luo Meiting is
這駱美婷它的主要的作用是
When these neurotransmitters
當這些神經傳導物質
it recycles
它再回收
when recycle
recycle的時候呢
it holds it back
它把它抑制住
So it turns into saying there are too many of these substances
所以變成說這些物質太多了
so you can imagine
所以你可以想像
The result of having too many of these neurotransmitters
這些神經傳導物質太多的結果
is to become
是變成
You become very hyper
你人就變成非常hyper
you can't get in
你就進不下了
What about the result that you can't get in?
你進不下來的結果呢
Of course the first one will increase your sense of security
當然第一個它會增加你的保足感
But what?
可是呢
its main problem
它的最主要的問題呢
yes you will have a lot of problems
是你會有一大堆的問題就是
your heart beats faster
你心跳加快
blood pressure rise
血壓上升
because you can't get in
因為你進不下來
Then the half tongue is your dry mouth
然後半舌就是你口乾舌燥
then bored with insomnia
然後厭死失眠
Of course you're tired of death and insomnia
那當然你厭死失眠
people will lose weight
人就會瘦下來
But its problem is
可是它的問題是
will let you
會讓你
your whole life
你的整個生活
make your life happy
讓你生活上的作喜
will be completely insomnia
會完全的失眠
That is to say, in comparison with Luo Shixian just mentioned
就是說跟剛剛講的羅士仙來比較起來的話
this will be more serious
這個會比較嚴重
because it just regulates your hormones
因為它只要調控你的荷爾蒙
or regulate your neurotransmitters
或調控你的神經傳導物質
This is more serious
這個是比較嚴重
In front of Luo Shixian, he asked you to guide him.
那前面羅士仙他讓你指導沒辦法
Take a shower, you can use as much oil as possible
洗澡你頂多拉油就好了
In case it is wearing two pants
萬一就是褲子穿兩件
three is ok
三件都沒關係
That's the one that directly affects your daily life.
那可是這個直接影響你的生活作息
that would be quite troublesome
那個就會蠻困擾的
Then they also found out that
那後來他們還發現說
because some people ate
因為有一些人吃了
some cardiovascular diseases
也會有引起一些心血管疾病
so what
那所以呢
US Food and Drug Administration
美國的食品藥物管理局
FDA
FDA
It is food and drug administration
就是food and drug administration
Funding Pharmacology Continental Doctors
資金藥理大陸醫生
because of the many reports
因為聽到很多的報告
So they were last year in 2001
所以他們在去年2001年的時候
He just said he had a limit
他就說他有一個限制
That is, people over the age of 65
就是說65歲以上的人
be careful when eating
吃的時候要特別小心
That's because of a lot of bad reports
那因為很多不良的報告
because of many side effects
因為很多副作用
So Abe Pharmaceuticals in
所以雅伯藥廠在
Because he had a warning from the FDA in August
因為他8月的時候FDA提出警告
He will do his best in time
他在時間內就絕對盡
Removed from the U.S. market
從在美國市場就下架
Because this will lead to a lot of legal litigation issues
因為這個到時候會牽到很多法律的訴訟問題
they can't afford it
他們賠不起
So at the moment, although the silver quality sounds good
所以目前雖然銀質很好聽
Loviting
羅維廷
But the problem is that his stock price may be as low as Lo Weiting
可是問題是他可能股價也羅維廷
So he finally had to quit
所以他最後只好下架
Therefore, currently available diet pills
所以目前能夠用的減肥藥
And it's safer that Mr. Ross
而且比較安全的是羅斯先
The next three to ask us are Welcom
接下來三個要問我們是衛爾剛
He Wergon's this
他這衛爾剛的這個
Drug development is also very interesting
藥物的研發也非常有趣
Of course Wei Ergang, of course everyone, as the name suggests
當然衛爾剛當然各位顧名思義
That is, he would tell us to make up for the dysfunction
就是他會我們說補起功能的障礙
then why
那為什麼呢
Because in fact, it didn’t mean that we must develop this
因為其實當初也不是說一定要開發這個
Because I don't think pharmaceutical companies will develop this specifically
因為我想不會藥廠特別去開發這個
No one has ever developed this sexual function before their disorder
之前沒有人會去開發這個性功能他們的障礙
He's actually mostly at that Pfizer factory.
他其實主要是在那個輝瑞藥廠
Their lab over here in the UK
他們在這個英國那邊的實驗室
They want this one for high blood pressure and heart and foot pain
他們想要針對高血壓跟心腳痛的這個
diseases for drug development
疾病來做藥物研發
Everyone knows
各位知道
Our blood pressure is regulated in many different ways
我們的血壓的調控是有很多不同的方式
one of them is
其中一種是
due to constriction of blood vessels
因為血管的收縮與否
It directly affects blood pressure
它會直接影響到血壓
It's like today if a water pipe
就好像今天如果是一個水管
You press hard on your water pipe
你的水管你把用力壓
Of course the water pressure changes
當然水壓都變
If the material of this water pipe
那如果說這個水管的材質
To loosen or loosen the material
把變鬆或是變得比較鬆散的材質
the blood pressure will get worse
那血壓就變差
So the idea was to say
所以當時的想法是說
if i could develop a drug
如果我能夠開發一個藥物
relax the muscles of the blood vessels
讓它血管的肌肉鬆弛
lower blood pressure
血壓就會降低
So they hoped to say
所以他們當初是希望說
Using the contraction or relaxation of this vascular muscle
利用這種血管肌肉的收縮或鬆弛與否
To treat high blood pressure and new foot pain
來治療高血壓跟新腳痛
Unexpectedly, it failed during the human experiment
結果沒想到在人體實驗的時候失敗
As a result, you will feel that doctors and nurses are very powerful
結果你會覺得說醫生跟護士很厲害
Although failed
雖然失敗
But he noticed that
可是他卻注意到說
Every one of these infectious patients will have thin gas
這個染性的病人每一個都會有薄氣
Of course, if the nurse sees what he thinks
那當然如果護士看他覺得說
maybe because i'm pretty
可能是因為我漂亮
Then this sushi patient reacted to me
那這個壽司的病人對我有反應
of course he is happy
他當然很開心
But this nurse I think he's the same as Felan
可是這個護士我想他跟Felan 一樣
also very careful
也非常小心
He noticed that I might not look good
他注意到我長得可能不怎麼樣
Why every patient sees me like this
為什麼每一個病人都看到我會這樣子
So he went to report to Fighter
所以他去報告Fighter
Fighter must say this is a good thing
就Fighter就一定說這個是好事情
So let's just not do that clinical test for high blood pressure.
所以我們乾脆就不要做那個高血壓的臨床測試
let's try
我們來試試看
Is it possible to win the above question?
這個是可不可以來博取上面的問題
because it's the same
因為也是一樣
These are also blood vessels to increase his blood flow
這個同樣都是血管是讓他的血流增加
So his blood flow on the air mass side can increase
所以他在性氣塊那邊的血流能夠增加
Just Arrive
就是就到達博取
so what about the drug
所以這個藥物呢
It's a drug that looks like this
是看起來是這樣子的藥物
We think Syndana Fuel
我們認為Syndana Fuel
The most important thing I just said is
最主要的他我剛剛講過是
We control the relaxation of blood vessels
我們控制血管的鬆弛
called Psychogenp
叫做Psychogenp
Psychogenp mainly controls the drooping of blood vessels
Psychogenp主要是控制血管的疏髒
Then this Psychogenp has a decomposed effect number
那這個Psychogenp它有一個分解的效數
called PdE5
叫做PdE5
This is called Fastal Diasdase
這個叫做Fastal Diasdase
That is to say
也就是說
PsychoGNV breaks it down
PsychoGNV把它分解了
Then they found
那結果他們發現
This Vahua this drug molecule
這個Vahua這個藥物分子
to inhibit its decomposition effect
去抑制它的分解效數
just make it indestructible
就讓它不能分解
So it became more and more like this PsychoGNV
所以變成說這個PsychoGNV就變多了
So this PsychoGNV has been regulating
那所以這個PsychoGNV一直去調控
Let this blood vessel relax and relax
讓這個血管一直鬆弛鬆弛
So it means that the blood flow keeps increasing
所以等於是這個血流就增加一直增加
That's certainly possible for the blood vessels of the heart
那當然可能對於心臟的血管
Because it may be relatively thick, it may be difficult to get the effect
因為可能是比較粗可能很難得到效果
But for the sexual organs, I think it's just right
可是對於性器官那邊覺得剛好
just happened to come across
就是剛好碰到了
to relax the blood vessels
就讓血管能夠鬆弛
then get engorged
然後得到充血
That's because of the result
那因為這樣的結果
These three can get Nobel Prize
這三個可以要得到諾貝爾江
But he didn't find Wei Erjiang
可是他不是發現韋爾江
don't know don't get me wrong
不知道不要誤會
Because finding Verjan is
因為找到韋爾江是
There are dozens and Werjiang
有數十還有韋爾江
Then why did they win the Nobel Prize?
那他們為什麼得諾貝爾江
Because I just talked about this PsychoGNV
是因為剛剛講到這個PsychoGNV
it's a physiological process
它這個生理的過程
In fact we found that
事實上我們發現是
Nitrogen Oxide
這個異氧化氮Nitrogen Oxide
There is this small molecule Nitrogen Oxide
有這種小分子Nitrogen Oxide
it actually goes to our message
它事實上會去對我們的訊息傳導
This clause has a great function
這條款有很大的功能
Then the last game is because of the discovery
那這上一顆的遊戲就是因為發現
Same as Nature Outside
跟Nature Outside一樣
seems to be about the whole biological process
好像有關整個生理過程
of course
那當然
Of course, in addition to this new board
當然也除了這個新局板之外
It is also related to the Biohagra we just talked about
也跟我們剛剛講的Biohagra有關
So they got the Nobel Prize in 1998
所以他們在1998年得了諾貝爾獎
well that
好 那
What about this Biohagra?
這個Biohagra呢
let me tell you
我跟各位講一下
Although it was discovered by accident
雖然是意外發現
But it made Pfizer very profitable
可是它讓輝瑞的獲利非常大
FDA passed it in 1998 and it can be sold
在98年有FDA通過它可以銷售
Then you see it was only two years around 2000
然後你看才兩年時間在2000年左右的時候
Its deferred sales have reached 1 billion US dollars
它的延銷售額就已經達到美金的10億美金
a B chain
一個B鏈
That is equivalent to about ten billion Taiwan dollars.
那相當於我們台幣大概是百多億
Then what
然後呢
How about in 2000?
待當時2000年的時候呢
Vagra is the whole
Vagra是整個
We say that in the global market
我們說全球市場裡面
sexual dysfunction
就治療性功能障礙
it accounts for 92%
它占了92%
But from 2000 to 2007, great changes
可是2000年到2007年的時候就很大的變化
what about this time
這個時候呢
I also just saw its sales drop by more than half
我也剛它的這個銷售額降了一半以上
why
為什麼呢
time for its success tax
到時候因為它的成功稅
Other pharmacies later joined the development
後來有其他藥房加入開發
So this one called Celis's Cd4
所以這個叫Celis的Cd4
with another drug
跟另外一個藥
I don't know what the Chinese name is called Leventral
我不知道中文名叫什麼叫Leventral
These two drugs come to share this market
這兩個藥物來分享這個市場
so he
所以他
and then what else
然後另外呢
Everyone knows this little blue ball
各位也知道這個藍色的小丸子
so in many countries
所以在很多國家
There are some for the production of medicine
都有一些為藥的產生
so what
所以呢
his
他的
Then another question he has is
然後另外他有一個問題就是
He's fat
他這個有塞一肥
He is asking us to stuff a fat
他是問我們塞一肥
because you know
因為各位知道
already this medicine
已經是這個藥
certainly
當然
because it is hope
因為是希望是說
This drug our trust can
這藥我們的信託能災
he will
他也會
against this other aspect of the vessel
針對這個其他方面的血管
So there are also reports that
所以也有報告是說
Also has an effect on neovascular disease
對於新血管疾病也有影響
that's the pair of eyes
那也有是對眼睛
because there are some
因為有一些
For example, patients with diabetes mellitus
比如說糖藥病的病人
his this
他的這個
ah
啊
That blood vessel in the retina is very fragile
視網膜的那個血管是非常脆弱的
Then if you let him bleed
那如果說你那邊讓他沖血的時候
If your eyes bleed
眼睛一出血的話
often easily blind
通常很容易造成失明
So these stuffed
所以這些塞一肥
so let everyone
所以讓大家
for this
對於這個
Let the doctor take the medicine
讓醫生在用藥的時候
he will be more cautious
他會比較謹慎
will be replaced by other
會用其他的替代
After talking about weight-loss pills and life-enhancing pills,
講完了剛剛減肥藥跟提高生活品質的藥之後
Let's talk about cancer drugs first
我們先來講抗癌藥物
There are several anticancer drugs
抗癌藥物其實有幾種
The five types I use here
我這邊用講的五種
I just want to tell you
我只想跟各位講說
In fact, the research and development of anticancer drugs has actually been going on for decades.
我們事實上抗癌藥物的研發其實在幾十年就有
R&D at the time was actually relatively non-selective
當時的研發事實上是比較沒有選擇性的
Which means it's probably just cancer cells
也就是說很可能只是說癌細胞
it grows faster than this cell
它長得比這長得細胞快
if we say we kill
如果說我們痛殺
The cancer cells will die more
那癌細胞會死得比較多
So people will talk about comparing non selective
所以人家會講到比較 non selective
not selective
沒有選擇性的
Like this Wufu urinating to avoid illness and Shunbo
像這個五福尿尿避病跟順波
I'll talk later
我等一下會講
Then compare selective therapy
然後比較 selective therapy
San Zhun
就是這樣子三準
Iris or Estin
Iris or 埃斯廷
Look at this Abosting
你看這個 Abosting
it's called cancer
它叫癌
I'll stop thinking about it for myself
我會自己想一想它就停下來
it's fun to name something
取名之類是很有趣
that said first
那首先講的
these two
這兩個
Uracial we call Uracial
Uracial我們稱為尿密定
We call this symbol Fo
這個符我們稱為Fo
This is a chemical therapy
這個是一個化學的療法
Basically it's just like normal Uracial
基本上它只是跟正常的Uracial
The molecule of uridine is missing a Fo
尿密定的分子是差了一個Fo
Because usually we speak chemically
因為通常我們在化學上來講
The size of this Fo floating fat
這個Fo 浮原脂的這個size
It's the same size as our pro
它的尺寸跟我們親的尺寸是一樣的
So if here
所以如果在這邊的話
if you take it as a waist
你把它當成腰的話
may trick the enzymes on the body
可能會欺騙身體上面的酵素
So this person means
所以這個人也就是說
It is basically the same as our natural medicine
它就根本上跟我們天然的這個藥品是一樣
So this was used very early
所以這個是很早很早用的這個
Chemotherapy used 40 years ago
40年前就在使用的化學療法
very primitive
非常原始
So what I just said is that
所以我剛剛講過就是說
Because IcBioxin is faster
因為IcBioxin比較快
So it will take more of this medicine
所以它會吃了比較多這種藥
Then kill IcBioxin
然後就把IcBioxin殺掉
The main mode of action is to say
那主要作用方式就是說
When the genetic information of our human body
當我們人體的遺傳訊息
When DNA is to be synthesized
DNA要做合成的時候
it will not be clear
它會生不清楚
It thought it was its medicine
它以為這是它藥的東西
just eat it in
就把它吃進來
after eating
吃進來之後
It finds that it has no way to make a copy
它發現它沒有辦法去做進一個複製
So DNA replication stops
所以DNA的複製就中止了
The same reason is to say
一樣的道理就是說
The iC package also has the normal C package
iC包也有正常C包
it's not optional
這是沒有什麼選擇性的
Just to say that the iC bag will grow faster
只是說一來說 iC包會長得比較快而已
Next is SysPlanetine
再來是SysPlanetine
just smooth
就是順薄
why is it called shun
為什麼叫順
It is Sys
就是Sys
Mainly the chemical structure above
主要是化學結構式上面
its this
它的這個
This Lygon of the two
這兩個的這個Lygon
Compounds are all on the same side
綽合物都在同一邊
we say Sys
我們說Sys
Shun Bo
叫順薄
that's the same
那也是一樣的
This is in the history of our chemotherapy
這個是在我們化療史上
The first one is very metallic
第一個很有金屬
especially if it is very thin
尤其是很有薄的話
i am platinum
我是白金
So this drug should be very expensive
所以這個藥應該非常值錢
very valuable
非常值錢
and platinum
還有白金
That
那
then it mainly can of course
那它主要當然可以
Can be applied to a variety of cancers
可以適用於各式各樣的癌症
So here's a talk about meat flow
所以這邊有講說肉流
or a tumor
或是腫瘤
or impending cancer
或是臨發癌
There are knots
結株都有
that same
那一樣
The drug ran into the DNA
這個藥物跑到DNA裡面
it will happen
它會發生
What we call ENA
我們稱為ENA的
Costing
Costing
it's called cross join
它叫交叉連結
It's like it's sticky
等於是它會亂黏
It's like when DNA replicates
等於是在DNA複製的時候
it's the result of it being sticky
它因為它亂黏的結果
inhibit the replication of its DNA
讓它DNA的複製受到抑制
So with its genetic message
所以跟它那個遺傳訊息
So as a result of this the cell dies easily
所以因為這樣的結果細胞就很容易死亡
But his worse result is that he used it for a long time
可是他比較差的結果就是用了久了
if you reply
假如說你回復的話
the patient will
這個病人會
Your tumor will be drug resistant anyway
你的腫瘤會反正抗藥性
So when this medicine has been used for a while
所以這個藥用了一段時間的時候
If unfortunately relapse
如果不幸復發的時候
you have to take other medicine
你必須用其他的藥
So it looks like it's time for cancer treatment
所以看來就是癌症療的時候
The doctor should pay close attention
就醫生要很密切的去注意
the patient's response to the drug
病人對藥物的反應
if the reaction is bad
如果反應不好
Or when there is drug resistance, change it as soon as possible
或是有抗藥性的時候要趕快換
Otherwise there is always
不然的話總有
actually grows very fast
事實上長得非常快
but no time to wait for him
但是沒有時間去等他的
Those first two are not optional
那前兩個是沒有選擇性的
i just said
我剛才講說
Both normal and cancer cells actually eat it
正常細胞跟癌細胞事實上都會吃它
But these drugs
可是現在講的這些藥物
is more selective
是比較選擇性的
like paclitaxel
像紫三醇
Taisheng
紫三醇有叫做台生的
called TACSO
叫TACSO
you see its tacso
你看它的TACSO
This name is very knowledgeable
這個命名很有學問
Why is it called purple triol?
為什麼叫紫三醇呢
because mainly in the 60s
因為主要是在60年代
he found in the pacific
他發現在太平洋
This is the West Coast of the United States
是美國的這個西岸
His entertainment is in the United States
他那邊的遊藝在美國
Northern Oregon
北部Oregon
Washington over there
Washington那邊
There are many redwood mountains along their coasts
他們的沿海都有很多紅木山
Redwood Mountain they call Pacific Purple Mountain
紅木山他們叫做太平洋紫山
Experienced from within his bark
從他的樹皮裡面體驗出來
Because of the Pacific Purple Mountain
因為有太平洋紫山
Because the purple mountain that came out was stupid
因為出來的紫山蠢
This drug is actually very famous
這個藥物其實也非常有名
Why? Because Zishan is stupid mainly to suppress this
為什麼?因為紫山蠢主要是抑制這個
because when the cell is about to replicate again,
因為我們在細胞要再做複製的時候
it will do a wet split
它就會做一隻有濕分裂
when wet split
有濕分裂的時候
Sales Galenton start above their casing
Sales Galenton他們的圍管上面開始
It is to make some insect groups on the surrounding pipes
就是圍管上要做一些蟲組
It is mainly when the worm group around the tube
它主要是讓圍管的蟲組的時候
hold back in the process
過程中要抑制住
So this comparison Selective
所以這個比較Selective
Why? Because the packet splitting will become faster
為什麼?因為包的分裂上會變得比較快
So if you can suppress this
所以如果你能夠去抑制這個
The Sambler that surrounds the pipe
圍管的這個Sambler
effectively inhibit the cancer cells
有效的去抑制這個癌細胞
This purple mountain idiot is actually very interesting
這個紫山蠢事實上也很有趣
In the United States, they spent a lot of manpower on the development
美國他們花了很多人力在開發
at that time
那當時
at this
在這個
there are some pharmaceutical factories
有一些藥廠
they actually do
他們其實這樣
already started to do
已經要開始要做
measure a little time
量一點時間
you have to notice
你要注意到
This is Supi
這個是素皮
You can't just cut off all the plain skin on the west coast of the Pacific Ocean
你不可能是把太平洋西岸的素皮全部都把它砍掉
Supi get it Supi
素皮把它得到素皮
that is
那個是
because they found out that it might be
因為他們發現說可能要
Supi may only cure a few diseases
就素皮可能只能治幾個病而已
So they then went to find some way
所以他們那時候去找出一些方法
able to mass produce this molecule
能夠量產這個分子
You see this molecule is very complex
你看這個分子是非常複雜的
That just so happens that we are in Taiwan
那剛好其實我們台灣
all 20 years ago
都在20年前
Yong Feng in this company
勇豐於這個公司
He actually wants to do BioTek
他事實上想要做BioTek
I think Wang Shuyuan, if someone has
我想王術遠長人如果有
should know the process
應該知道這個過程
They sent a professor from Taiwan
他們有派台灣某個教授
to follow
去跟
want to go
想要去
Get this Technology
拿到這個Technology
used to take
用拿的
i don't know how to get it
我不知道怎麼拿的
but
不過
just bad luck
剛好運氣不好
Just got caught by the FBI
剛好被FBI的
buy line
買一線
Just got caught
剛好一網被抓到
So they had some legal action at the time
所以他們那時候有一些法律訴訟
so the professor
所以那個教授
lived there for a while
還在那邊住了一段時間
to come back
才能回來
This is some biotechnology
這個是有一些biotechnology
Know-how in biotechnology is actually very important
生物科技這樣的know-how其實很重要
Because you originally had to get out of the plain skin
因為你本來你必須要從素皮裡面
Then how do you go about mass producing this next?
那接下來你要怎麼樣去量產這個
actually a big problem
事實上是一個很大的問題
like we were watching this
就好像我們當時在看這個
Pan Lin's New Year mass production is the same
潘林新年量產一樣
That's a very important technology
那都是一個很重要的科技
Well then it's IRISA
好那再來是IRISA
IRIS
IRISA
What about IRISA?
這IRISA呢
In fact, the main role is in this
這個事實上主要作用的是在這個
epithelial growth factor
上皮生長因子
Then this IRISA is actually very famous
那這IRISA事實上是很有名
Especially in dealing with this lung cancer
尤其是在對付這個肺癌方面
Then why is it for
那為什麼它是對於
We say the receptor for epithelial growth factor
我們說上皮生長因子的受體
We say we say EGFR
我們說我們說EGFR
Epidermal
就Epidermal
Gross Factor Receptor
Gross Factor Receptor
that means
那等於是說
In general, many processes in our body
一般來講我們身體的很多過程
including the replication of its cells
包括它細胞的複製
are subject to this signal
都受到這個signal
inside the signal
signal裡面
Let's say it has a message delivery event
就說它有一個訊息的傳遞的事件
one of them is
那其中一個就是
epithelial growth factor
這個上皮生長因子
That
那
Ic cell, if it can grow rapidly
Ic胞它如果能夠快速生長已經
So his messaging will be very strong
所以他的訊息傳遞會非常旺盛
So IRISA is one of the
所以IRISA是其中把
It's like a drug
等於是藥物呢
which puts a very important message
其中把一個很重要的訊息
let him pass the message
讓他這個訊息傳遞
There is no way to transfer smoothly
傳遞沒有辦法順利的去傳
so beijing says
所以北京說
After he inhibited this EGFR
他抑制到這個EGFR以後
After this epidermal growth factor
這個上皮生長因子以後
After acceptor
受體以後
let this cancer cell
讓這個癌細胞的
no way
沒有辦法
because he needed information
因為本來他需要訊息
message received
接受到訊息
This cancer cell is able to grow
這癌細胞才能夠增長
to be able to transfer
才能夠轉移
Even more severe drug resistance
甚至產生更嚴重的抗藥性
Then you once you pass this message on the way
那你一旦你把這個訊息傳遞的途徑
block it later
把它阻斷以後
Cancer cells cannot continue to grow
癌細胞就沒有辦法繼續增長
continue to transfer
繼續轉移
So this is a
所以這個是一個
For now
目前來講
Our very effective anti-cancer drug
我們非常有效的一個抗癌的藥法
And then there's Albostin
然後再來是Albostin
This cancer wet court
這癌濕庭
Then this Albostin and the previous drugs
那這個Albostin跟前面的這些藥物
no the same
不一樣
because it is not a drug molecule
因為它不是一個藥物分子
Rather it is a
而是它是一個
What we call a monoclonal antibody
我們稱為是一個單株的抗體
a big protein
很大的一個 protein
This Humanized Monoclonal Antibody
這個Humanize Mococlon Antibody
is a monoclonal antibody
是一個單株抗體
then it is mainly
那它主要的是
We are primarily conscious in our
我們是主要是意識在我們的這個
What we call Angiogenesis is angiogenesis
我們稱為Angiogenesis 就是血管生成
that is, cancer cells
就是說癌細胞
If it grows fast today
今天如果長得很快
it has to keep growing
它必須不斷的增長
or even say it's going somewhere else
或甚至說它要跑到別的地方
when cancer cells are about to grow
癌細胞要增長的時候
Must be a lot of nutrients in the apartment
一定要很多養分在公寓
like a baby growing up
就好像嬰兒要長大
It must drink milk non-stop every day
它每天一定要不停的去喝牛奶一樣
cancer cells too
癌細胞也是一樣
So it must distinguish some factors
所以它必須分明一些因子
Let nearby capillaries escape
讓附近的微血管跑出來
Then it's like adding the oil pipe in
然後等於是把油管加進來
provide it with nutrients
提供它養分
We call this process consanguinity
我們稱為這個過程叫血緣生成
Angiogenesis is called Angiogenesis
就血管生成叫Angiogenesis
that process is very important
那這個過程是非常重要的
then we are now
那我們現在是
They just discovered that using this monoclonal antibody
他們就是發現說用這個單株抗體
able to put this
能夠把這個
Regulate the branch of its bloodline generation
調控它這個血緣生成的這個分
This process blocks it
這個過程把它做阻斷
So it is equal to the cancer wet body, the drug
所以呢等於是這個癌濕體這個藥物
can make this cancer cell able to
可以讓這個癌細胞能夠
stop growing up at least
都停止長大至少
So usually it can be used with other chemotherapy
所以通常它可以等於是跟其他的化療一起使用
Then it means that it may allow cancer cells to control the
然後就是說它可能讓癌細胞控制到
let it grow
讓它去長大
that can be combined with other anticancer drugs
那可以配合其他的抗癌藥物
let it go on let it die
讓它繼續讓它死亡
What if the drug is unfortunate?
那如果很不幸的這個藥物呢
Also at the end of last year
也在去年年底的時候呢
The FDA found that
FDA發現說
This drug is actually for the metastasis of cancer cells
這個藥物其實對於癌細胞的轉移
completely gone
完全沒有了
no obvious curative effect
就沒有明顯的療效
So the FDA said last year
所以FDA在去年的時候說
Abosting is best not used to treat this metastatic cancer
Abosting最好不要用在處理這個可以轉移的癌症上
Then of course you can use
那當然你可以用在
This if cancer cells
這個如果癌細胞
It can be used if it is swollen cancer
如果是腫癌症的時候是可以用
but for
可是對於
That is, cancers that can metastasize malignantly have no obvious curative effect
就是可以惡性轉移的癌症是沒有明顯的療效
A big hit for this company
對於這個這家公司一個很大的打擊
They target cancer cell metastasis
他們是針對癌細胞轉移
It was found to be inactive
結果發現是沒有活性
so cancer wet court
所以癌濕庭
So cancer shouldn't stop
所以應該癌不能停了
cancer can't stop
癌不能停了
OK, let's talk about
好 接下來我們再講到
that's not stethamine
那不是藏胺
it's basically this
它基本上是這個
we are all a sugar
我們都是一個糖類
this sugar
就是這個糖類
What about glucosamine?
那其實葡萄糖胺呢
Basically it's inside our body
基本上它是我們身體裡面
Chondroitin
軟骨素
We say chondroitin
我們說軟骨素
In which connective tissue are we generally
一般我們在那個節地組織
This cartilage between the bone and the heel bone
骨跟骨之間的這個軟骨
is to make it an important ingredient
是讓它是一個重要成分
so because we say
所以因為我們說
Glucosamine is important
葡萄糖胺重要是
Say if the bones are bad
說如果說骨頭不好啊
Said that the joints are not good, you need to eat glucosamine
說關節不好要吃葡萄糖胺
Let me tell you about it
那這邊跟各位講一下
your
你的
that is
就是說
Glucosamine
葡萄糖胺
It has nothing to do with calcium
就是跟鈣是完全沒有關係
Because glucosamine it is a
因為葡萄糖胺它是一個
a monosaccharide molecule
一個單糖的分子
Calcium is a mineral
那鈣它是一個礦物
is something different
是不一樣的東西
Then everyone knows that is to say
那各位知道就是說
It means that if you eat today
等於是說如果你今天吃
Glucosamine
葡萄糖胺
because it is in our body
因為它是在我們要身體
You are going to synthesize this
你們要合成這個
cartilage time
軟骨的時候
it's just a raw material
它是一個原料而已
Raw material only
原料而已
so you eat more
所以你吃了越多
It can make your cartilage grow more
它可以讓你軟骨長得比較
That is to say, it should be outside of your growth rate
就是說應該你的生長數以外
because of U.S
因為我們
Generally speaking, patients with joints
一般來講關節的病人
we are getting older
我們年紀大了
etc.
等等
The formation and decomposition of cartilage must be balanced
軟骨的生成跟分解是要去平衡
Therefore, more raw materials must be added
所以必須補充比較多的原料
Let it grow and decompose a little bit in balance
讓它生長跟分解能夠稍微平衡一下
So we say Prolana is a healthy food
所以我們說Prolana是一個健康食品
English is called Dietary Supplement
英文叫做Dietary Supplement
words also spoken in the United States
也在美國來講的話
besides vitamins
除了維他命之外
except for minerals
除了礦物之外
It is one of the most commonly used a health food
它是一個最常用的一個健康食品
The second one is pineapple acid
那第二個是菠蘿酸
it is also a sugar
它也是一個糖
Bromelain is a monosaccharide
菠蘿酸是一個單糖
That pineapple acid is a polysaccharide
那菠蘿酸它是一個多糖
In fact, this polysaccharide
那這個多糖事實上
It is a regular polysaccharide
它是個有規則的多糖
because its repeating unit is a disaccharide
因為它的重複的單位是一個雙糖
that one is called what we think
那一個是稱為我們認為
gluconic acid
葡萄糖酸
That's another case of glucose
那另外是葡萄糖案
This is equivalent to a disaccharide
這等於是一個雙糖
Then you see
那各位看到
What's interesting about this molecule above is that
這上面的這個分子比較有趣的是
it has a lot of skin charge
它有很多膚電荷
So because of the repulsion the malleability of this molecule is very good
所以因為排斥這個分子的延展性非常好
And it has a lot of guns that can work with water
而且它很多這個槍機可以跟水作用
So what's interesting about this molecule is that it stretches very high
所以這個分子有趣是它延展非常高
will become sticky
會變黏黏的
In addition, its water and ability are very good
另外就是它的這個水和能力非常好
so moisturizing
所以保濕
So it is equal to the pot why uric acid is often used in cosmetics
所以等於是鍋尿酸為什麼常常用在化妝品
There is nothing wrong with the effect of moisturizing
有保濕的效果那是沒有錯的
ad didn't lie to you
廣告沒有騙你
Then I just said that these pots of uric acid are also present in our body.
那我剛剛講過這些鍋尿酸我們身體裡面也有
That's usually used in our energy-saving organizations
那通常是用在我們節力組織
There is also so much uric acid on the epidermis and nerve tissue
還有表皮還有神經組織上面有這麼多的這個鍋尿酸
That's about a normal person weighing 70 kg
那大概一個正常人70公斤的一個正常人
About 15 grams of pot uric acid
大概有15克的鍋尿酸
That in pot uric acid supremacy is currently recognized
那在鍋尿酸至上目前已經被認可
I mean, if you say we have joint problems
是說你如果說我們說關節有問題
especially the knee
尤其是膝部的關
You can directly apply the pot of uric acid
你可以直接施打鍋尿酸
because it is aimed at osteoarthritis patients
因為它針對於骨關節病人
it is there
它是有
Didn't mention your osteoarthritis patient
沒說你的骨關節病人
There is a problem with uric acid in this cartilage pot
它這邊的這個軟骨鍋尿酸有問題
After the beating, let its substance be
施打以後讓它的物質就是
don't wear out too fast
不要磨損特別快
Because this cartilage is
因為這個軟骨是
Numbing agent between bones
骨頭跟骨頭之間的弄麻劑
If you don't have that substance
那你沒有那物質的話
direct bone-to-bone contact
骨頭跟骨頭之間會直接接觸
that's like
那等於是
have an effect on bone and joint function
會有骨關節能的作用
That
那
This is in addition to the treatment of bone and joint function
這是除了這骨關節能的治療之外呢
usually
一般來講
Osteonasic acid can also
骨納酸也可以
I just said that it is used in cosmetics
我剛剛講過用在化妝品
And the FDA US Food and Drug Administration in 2003
那而且FDA美國食品藥物管理局在2003年的時候
he also said
他也說
if we say
如果說我們
If an older person wants to remove wrinkles
年級大的人他想要除皺紋的話
Then you can directly administer osteosarcin
那你可以直接施打骨納酸
Because just said he has moisturizing
因為剛剛講他有保濕
It's good to keep his ductility
保留他延展性也好
So it is equivalent to filling wrinkles
所以等於是可以填補皺紋
Facial wrinkle
Facial wrinkle
So this is
那所以說這個是
his output is very large
他的產量非常大
that you know
那各位知道
Osteonasic acid
以前一開始的骨納酸
inside to grow
裡面去生長
Because it is the organ that allows the attack to contain
因為是讓攻擊的機關裡面含
very high
非常高
It just so happens that few people eat organs, right?
那剛好沒有人很少人吃機關嘛對不對
in often few people
在常常很少人
so before
所以以前
Osteonasic acid is separated from this organ
骨納酸是從這個機關裡面去分離出來
that now yields
那現在產量
too much demand
需求量太大了
So there are other ways to do production
所以有其他的方式來做生產
Okay, that's over. Just now.
好了 那講完了剛剛
Our weight loss pills, I also just talked about other than health products
我們減肥藥 我也剛跟健康品之外
Let's talk about painkillers now
我們現在來講止痛藥
There is also a very interesting story in the painkiller
那止痛藥裡面這邊也是一個非常有趣的故事
For example, we will talk about R-Spinning, how to find
比如說我們會講到R-Spinning 那怎麼樣發現
What additional benefits does it have
它有什麼樣的另外附加的好處
it has some disadvantages
那它有一些壞處
But what we're going to talk about here is
不過我們這邊要講的說
Other than R-Spinning
其他除了R-Spinning之外
Now you see in your daily life
目前你們日常生活看到
For example, this is called this place
比如說這個稱為這個處安分
In fact, it is Pronatex
事實上就是普拿疼
You saw in the report a few days ago that
你們前幾天在報道上有看到說
Children who eat too much Puna pain will affect their health
小孩子吃太多普拿疼會影響到沒因素的
This is Puna pain
這個叫普拿疼
Then there is IP-Profan
然後就是IP-Profan
In addition, we will talk about some Costone
那另外就是我們會講到一些Costone
What is Costone, people will listen to you to explain
Costone是什麼 人家會聽各位做個解釋
R-Spinning is also an old drug
R-Spinning也是一個老藥
in fact its history
事實上它的歷史
was launched in 1899
是在1899年上市的
The pan energy that I talked about at the beginning of today will last longer
今天一開始講的這個潘能性還要久
that aspirin
那阿斯啤林
That's because it's a direct translation of aspirin
那因為這是直接翻碼就阿斯啤林
Then his official name is
那他的正式名稱叫
acetylcytocacyl
acetylcytocacyl
So you guys are saying this is a
那各位就是說這是一個
Acetylated salicylic acid
以西化的這個水洋酸
if this point
如果說這分
If it's not here, it's a salicylic acid
這邊沒有的話這就是一個水洋酸
usually we say
那通常我們講
This drug has three types
這藥物呢它有三種的
Why is this medicine so good?
說這個藥物怎麼這麼好
because it has many good activities
因為它有很多好的活性
first it can relieve pain
第一個它可以止痛
it's antipyretic it's anti-inflammatory
它會解熱 它抗發炎
Then we'll explain why it
那等一下我們會解釋為什麼它
There will also be this
同時會有這個
That is to say, an inflammatory reaction process of the body
就是說身體的一個發炎反應的過程
Notifies you when your body is emotional
身體有情緒的時候會通知你
So tell the body it will take the body temperature
所以通知身體它會把體溫
slightly higher
稍微增高一點
let your body react
讓你的那個身體的反應
will get faster
會變得比較快
That's because of your excessive inflammation.
那可是因為你過量的發炎反應
make your body look like it's not
讓你身體好像不是
So you must take this spoonful of medicine
所以你必須吃這匙通藥來
play out the process
演繁這個過程
That history is very long
那這個歷史非常久
because it was in BC
因為它在公元前
three or four hundred years ago
三四百年前就已經有
there is such a record
有這樣的記載
Why because at the time they made the willow bark
為什麼因為當時他們從柳樹皮
to experience
去體驗
What about the experience from inside the bark?
從有樹皮裡面體驗的東西呢
found that it can directly relieve pain
就發覺它直接可以止痛
And it can be said to be the pain when I was a child
而且它可以說生小的時候那種痛
Pain relief with tree bark extract
可以用有樹皮的萃取物來止痛
This is the record of the Greeks
這是希臘人他們的記載
The later record is that until 1875
那後來的記載就是到1875
What about the end of the 1970s?
1970世紀的末期呢
They discovered that this salicylic acid
他們發現這個水洋酸
Our name is Sodium Cylite
我們叫做Sodium Cylite
That's actually the one without the part
那事實上就是這個沒有這個部分
It's the acid part.
就是水洋酸的部分呢
In fact at that time it was using
事實上那個時候就在使用
As far as the end of 1875 and 1970
就1875、1970末期
That's just saying salicylic acid has some side effects
那只是說水洋酸有一些副作用
we'll get to that later
我們等一下會講到
The fact that the invention in Aspirin was actually made by this man
那在阿斯批林的發明的事實上是這位人手
is in Bayer Germany
是在拜爾德國
The basis of their chemistry in Germany is very
德國他們的化學的基礎非常
Then their chemist was Felix Hopmann
那當時他們的化學家叫Felix Hopmann
Well, in fact, his father, because of the joint
那他事實上他爸爸因為關節的關係
Always eat that salicylic acid
常常要吃那個水洋酸
But he complained to his son
可是他跟他兒子抱怨說
I take this salicylic acid
我吃這個水洋酸
There are often crashes
常常會有潰洋
And that is waiting
而且那個就是等
Our so-called kelp acid is from Lugulin
我們所謂的潰洋酸是蘆菇林的
some wounds inside the body
身體內部有一些傷口
often unpredictable
常常會沒辦法預測
so always with him
所以一直跟他
his child
他的小孩子
He said you work in a pharmacy
他說你在藥行做事
Then you will do chemistry again
然後你又會做化學
why doesn't he
他為什麼不
hold on let me out
等一下讓我出來一下
The results of it
結果呢
His son really took acid from this water
他兒子真的是把從這個水洋酸
to do all kinds of chemistry
去做各式各樣的化學
did some lalama baba test
做了一些拉拉麽巴巴試
so this is our first
所以這是我們第一個
one in history
歷史上的一個
human experiment
人的實驗
Just try him out
直接試他好不好上
That's a good thing he has good chemistry skills.
那還好他化學技巧還不錯
they have some
他們有一些
Some
一些
It's the medicine my student made for me
是我學生給我做的藥
I dare not eat
我不敢吃
Why
為什麼
Then in case there are some impurities
那萬一有一些雜質
eat it, i'm busy
吃下去我忙死掉
that's the end
那是完
so let his chemistry skills not bad
所以讓他的化學技巧還不錯
he eats
他把吃
turn out
結果發現
Added this acetylipop
加了這個acetylipop
westernized place
以西化的地方
the result is very good
結果非常好
so later
所以後來
this pharmaceutical factory
這個藥廠
their beyer company
他們拜爾的公司
decided to put this
就決定把這個
Originally they were producing salicylic acid
本來他們是在生產水洋酸
salicylic acid
就在生產以西化的水洋酸
This is our ASPY today
就是我們今天的ASPY
However, this story has also been overturned
不過這故事也有被推翻
why
為什麼呢
because at that time they said
因為那個時候他們就說
Germany was later contested by the Nazis
德國後來在納粹的競爭下
they were german
他們那時候是德國人
because later one
因為後來有一位
this
這個
Jewish chemist
猶太裔的化學家
They said it was his invention
他們說那個是他的發明
It was because the Nazis ruled at that time
就是因為納粹那個時候統治
He made up a story that
他有編一個故事說
There is a very filial chemist
有一個很孝順的化學家
Because he is filial to his father, he will make it
因為他孝順父親會做出來
I'm not a historian
這個我不是歷史學家
i can't go
我沒有辦法去
Say which one is right and both are wrong
說哪個對兩都是不對
But the name of Aspirinde is also very famous
不過阿斯批林德的命名也是很有名
A
A
he's mostly talking
他主要是在講說
Because he Westernized this salicylic acid
因為他把這個水洋酸做了以西化
THE SIEGE
SETIO
S-P-I-R-I-N
S-P-I-R-I-N
this is mainly
這是主要是
he was in
當時他在
In this 19th century
這個19世界的時候
experience from this plant
從這個植物裡面體驗出來的
the name of the plant
這個植物的名字
Then there is S-PRIM
然後就是S-PRIM
and this source
還有這個來源
So I just said 1899
所以我剛剛講說1899年
What about Bayer?
拜爾公司呢
Just put this on the market
就把這個推到市場上
That's what they did in 1999 AD
那就是他們在公元1999年
100 years later they have statistics
100年以後他們有統計
Currently the most used medicine bowl in the world
目前就是世界上用最多藥碗
He seems to have used over a billion medicine bowls
他好像已經用了超過10億顆的藥碗
Then you'll see this ad from 1923
那你會看到這1923年的廣告
you see migrant
你看到migrant
The name means neuralgia
這個名字是神經痛的意思
this is german
這個是德文
migrant this is arthritis
migrant這個是關節炎
rheumatoid arthritis
風濕性關節炎
matoioasuritis
matoioasuritis
You said ASPINE's medicine at that time
你說ASPINE當時的藥
Because of this related series Perish
因為這個相關系列Perish
It is an advertisement of ASPINE in Europe
就說是歐洲ASPINE的廣告
it can be trained to cure bottle headaches
它可以訓練治療瓶頭痛
neuralgia and joint pain
神經痛跟關節痛
Why does it have pain relief in ASPINE
ASPINE中為什麼它有止痛
Antipyretic and anti-inflammatory
解熱跟抗發炎
inside our body
是我們身體裡面
To initiate an inflammatory response like this
要啟動這樣子的發炎反應
In fact, it is made of our fat
事實上是由我們脂肪裡面
There is a four double sword
有一個四個雙劍
We say Tetraximic Acid
我們說四溪酸
Arachidonic acid
就Arachidonic acid
It is a twenty carbon fatty acid
它是一個二十個碳的脂肪酸
start here
從這裡面開始
to do some metabolic reactions
要做一些新陳代謝的反應
what about here
那這裡面呢
The first very important reaction is the itching reaction
第一部很重要的反應是癢化的反應
What we call sychroactogenase
我們稱為sychroactogenase
For example, the itching reaction starts
比如說這個癢化反應開始
Generate this Perish
產生這個Perish
Perish we call prostaglandins
我們稱為前列腺素的Perish
So why is it called Postagranding
所以那為什麼叫Postagranding
That has nothing to do with the prostate
那是跟前列腺一點關係都沒有
That is to say, this series of reactions of the body
就是說身體的這個一連串的反應
We call this an inflammatory response
我們稱為這是一個發炎的反應
That just happens to be this Aspirin or what we'll talk about later
那剛好這個Aspirin或是我們等一下要講的
this other pain medication
這個其他的止痛藥物
are all acting on this Cox
都是作用在這個Cox
That is to say, this epoxidation enzyme
就是說這個環氧化的這個酵素
Cox1 1 2
Cox1 1 2
so it blocks it
所以它把它阻撰了
equal to the following molecules
等於是下面這些分子
It's actually all about regulating our inflammatory response.
事實上都是去調控我們的發炎反應
For example, it will be excruciating
比如說它會有痛絕
With this, the body temperature can be raised
有這個有把體溫整高
Then what
然後呢
Inflammation of these molecules can no longer be produced
發炎的這些分子就沒有辦法產生了
So it's like shutting it down from the source
所以等於是從源頭就把它關起來
So we say its main purpose is to control the inflammatory response
所以我們說它的主要主要是去控制這個發炎反應
Mainly this Enzyme
主要是這個Enzyme
That is to say Cox
就是說Cox
I just mentioned
那我剛剛提過就是
it you turn off the principle
它你把原則關掉
So the latter
所以後面的這些
prostaglandins
這些前列腺素
This is not just a single Compound
這不只單一個Compound
Prostaglandin and blood cream
前列腺素跟血霜完內
Dipamine
就是雙巴腺素
These molecules are all related to the inflammatory response
這些分子這些後面都是跟發炎反應有關
regulate these physiological responses
調控這些生理反應的
just turn it all off
就是把全部關掉
And the front line counts it's actually a hormone
而且前線線數它事實上是一個荷爾蒙
In physiology, it is to transmit the pain sensation to the brain
在生理裡面是要傳遞把痛覺傳到腦子裡面
So it's time to say you have a painful inflammatory reaction today
所以變成說你今天起痛的發炎反應的時候
Excessive inflammation makes your physiological response not
過量的發炎反應讓你生理反應不是
So you have to use painkillers to shut this source down
所以你必須施動止痛藥把這個源頭就把它關起來
Then this aspirin is a miracle drug
那這個的阿斯比林他是個很神奇的藥物
So at the time it meant that even though I didn't know anything in 1940
所以當時就是說雖然在1940年的時候什麼都不知道
It is equivalent to listing it in 1899
等於是1899年就把它上市
But his physical
可是他的這個生理的
His entire passport is about why he can have such a magical effect
他整個passway就為什麼他能夠有這樣的神奇的效果
This perfectly explained until the 1950s by Gang Dan
這個完美的解釋一直到1950年代由Gang Dan
He clarified this Maconian with his technology
他把這個Maconian他的作用技術把它釐清住
So in 1982 he and two other
所以他在1982年跟另外兩位
I believe they should be Swedish chemistry
我相信他們應該是瑞典的化學
Shared Nobel Prize in Physiology or Medicine with Semmelson
跟Semmelson共同獲得諾貝爾獎的生理學或醫學獎
got it in 1982
在八二年的時候得到
In addition, aspirin is constantly
另外阿斯比林不斷的
because he is a magic molecule
因為他是神奇分子
Although Li Tong You Jiu
雖然利同優久
He doesn't just have pain relief
他不只是只是有止痛的效果
he has other
他還有其他
most importantly
最主要是
You can avoid it if you don't take low dose aspirin for a day
你一天只要不用低劑量的阿斯比林的話就可以去避免
Heavy wind heels
重風跟
Hard Attack
Hard Attack
on the occurrence of cardiovascular disease
就心血管疾病的發生
And they are experimentally confirmed
而且他們這個是有實驗證實的
Taiwan is relatively rare. If you go to the United States, you will see what they call Low Dose aspirin
台灣比較少如果你去美國要看到他們稱為Low Dose的阿斯比林
Generally, aspirin can be 50 or 80mm
一般到阿斯比林可以50或80mm
What do we say Primary
我們說有什麼Primary
Primary prevention is secondary prevention
一級的預防就二級預防
for these people
對於這些人
He has absolutely no history of cardiovascular disease
他完全沒有心血管疾病的歷史
His heart was completely fine before
以前他的心臟都完全沒事情
They found that he reduced cardiovascular disease by about a tenth
他們發現說他可以降低心血管疾病大概10分之一
For him, if he has had a stroke and has a background of cardiovascular disease
對於他如果有中過風有心血管疾病的底子
If he has some cardiovascular disease and myocardial infarction
他有一些心血管疾病有心肌梗塞這些問題的話
If you take low doses of RSP daily
如果你每天服用低劑量的RSP的話
He can also reduce the recurrence rate by 10%
他也可以降低再發生率的10%
So this effect is quite significant
所以這個效果是蠻顯著的
So generally speaking, they will recommend you for a day
所以一般來講他們都會推薦你一天
Yours can eat about 40 to 80 mini light is enough
你那個可以吃大概40到80個mini光就夠
can have such a preventive effect
就可以有這樣子的預防效果
So this is RSP and of course RSP has some problems
那這是RSP 那當然RSP還有一些問題
It's just that at the beginning we said that it actually causes some side effects
就是一開始我們講他事實上會導致一些副作用
Those side effects include children can not eat
那些副作用包括小孩子不能吃
may cause budding syndrome
可能導致有蕾濕症厚情
RSP he will cause you some itchy problems
RSP他會導致你一些潰癢的問題
Although this Hopman he solves his dad's problem
雖然這個Hopman他解決他爸爸的問題
But in fact, he still has the problem of itching after taking it for a long time.
可是事實上長期的服用他還是有潰癢的問題
Why do people explain
為什麼人家會解釋
So, they started looking for some other alternative medicine
那所以呢他們開始找一些其他的替代藥物
Those alternative medicines include RSP
那這些替代藥物包括RSP
non-inflammatory anti-inflammatory drugs
我們稱為非類部存抗發炎藥物
We call it NSP
我們稱為NSP
NSAID
NSAID
so why? because
那為什麼呢?因為
Steroid
Steroid
Just mentioned those Postacans
就剛剛講的那些Postacan
Steroid itself
Steroid本身
Steroid itself is an anti-inflammatory drug
Steroid本身就是一個消炎的藥物
we say it is
我們說它是
But Steroid has serious side effects
可是Steroid它會有很嚴重的副作用
So what we usually do is a
所以我們通常要搞的是一個
Non-Steroidal Anti-Inflammatory Drugs
非類固醇的一個抗發炎的藥物
on NSAIDs
就NSAID
the first one
那第一個
It is also famous in history
在歷史上也很有名的就是這個
Print paper
普拿特紙
就Aslamino fan
就Aslamino fan
touch light or
觸碰燈或是
Or in the US we call it Tan
或是在美國我們稱為Tan
Known as Panagl in Taiwan
在台灣稱為Panagl
It's paper
就是普拿特紙
It was on the market in the United States as early as 1953
那很早在1953年在美國就上市了
that they now think
那他們現在認為
Because of the fact that it has sold more than RSP
因為事實上它的銷售量已經超過RSP
And usually we say
而且通常我們說
This is a T token of RSP
這是RSP的一個T代物
that this
那這個
what about the painkiller
那個止痛藥呢
it actually
它事實上
you can now in
你現在就可以在
available in general medicines
在一般的藥物就可以買得到
You can buy beyond ingredients
超越食材就可以買得到
and it works really fast
而且它的效果非常快
because after you take
因為你服用以後
It takes about 11 minutes to have an analgesic effect
大概11分鐘就開始有止痛的效果
but very good
但是非常好
and it won't hurt the taste
而且它不會傷味
what about the other
那另外呢
its something on the upgrade side
它的在升級面的事
About one to four hours
時間大概大概一到四個小時
Then I just said that after the 1980s
那我剛剛講過在1980年代以後
Its sales volume has surpassed that of RSP
它的銷售量就已經超過了RSP
So the effect of Pronison is very good
所以這普拿臣的效果是非常好
what about the other
那另外呢
its
它的
Why was it called Tanel in the first place?
當初它為什麼叫Tanel
mainly because they found
就主要是因為他們發現
They also Campaign means
他們也Campaign就是說
it is small
它是小
Just talked about RSP
剛剛講RSP
Children are usually not allowed to use
小孩子通常是不能使用的
so they are
所以他們就是
This is the drug they started giving to the little ones
這是他們一開始給小孩子用的藥物
Tanel Children's Extra
Tanel Children's Extra
That
那
I really don't want to talk about its discovery
它的發現我真的不講了
time relationship
時間的關係
almost time
時間差不多了
I have to speed up a little bit
我必須把速度稍微加快
What about IP ProFan?
那IP ProFan呢
in what we call
在我們稱
Generally we call it ADV and there is a New Print
一般我們稱為ADV有一個New Print
What about the initial development?
那一開始的研發呢
Mainly in England there is a science called Steward Eddons
主要是在英國有一個科學叫Steward Eddons
Adams
亞當斯
He was looking for a drug
他本來是想要找一個藥物
able to treat him with this
能夠治療他的這個
the old one
舊以後的那個
Handover problem
Handover的問題
don't know how to speak english
不知道英文怎麼講
that is
就是
that
那個
hangover problem
宿醉的問題
Unexpectedly, this medicine turned out to be
結果沒想到這個藥竟然
No tax but the problem is it can have a painkiller effect
沒有輸稅可是問題是它可以有止痛的效果
So the effect is also very good
所以效果也非常好
Then this is a case of immediate selectivity
那這個是有立即選擇性的情況
In terms of time, I'll jump over first
時間關係我先跳過去
so-called selective painkillers
那所謂的具有選擇性的止痛藥
just now
就剛剛來講
In our inflammatory response PASS
就我們這個發炎反應PASS位裡面
Cox that NZ
Cox那個NZ
In fact it comes in two different forms
事實上它有兩種不同的形式
We use Cox1, Cox2
我們用Cox1、Cox2
Cox1 is ubiquitous
Cox1是普遍存在的
In fact it can protect you
事實上它是可以去保護你
The inside story of your provocation
你那個挑話到的內幕
so if you hold it back
所以如果你把它抑制住的話
it has no way to protect
它沒有辦法保護
so you get ulcers easily
所以你容易得到潰瘍
So Cox2 is when the inflammatory response
所以Cox2是發炎反應的時候
will be activated
才會被啟動的
So usually speaking
所以通常來講
We say like R-Speed-In
我們說像R-Speed-In
Usually it suppresses both
通常它會同時去抑制這兩個
so we are not good
所以我們不好
We say that after taking this medicine
我們說吃了這個藥以後
Although it can relieve pain
雖然可以止痛
But when reactivating for a long time
可是長期復動的時候
would be tantamount to destroying your consumption
會等於破壞你消耗
consume these mucous membranes
消耗到這些黏膜
is to reactivate
就是要復作用
so it becomes saying
所以變成說
At that time they thought that
當時他們想法就是說
Afraid to discover that there are these two different forms
怕發現有這兩種不同的形式
Then my medicine for the next generation
那我下一代的藥
Drugs must be suppressed
藥物一定要去抑制
Cox2 cannot inhibit Cox1
Cox2不能抑制Cox1
generally
一般上是這樣
but in fact
可是事實上
There is a problem
有發生問題
because
因為
One of the two major pharmaceutical companies in the United States is
在美國兩個大藥廠一個是
Merck one is Pfizer
默克一個是輝瑞
Bison
Bison
they went to find the so-called
他們去找出所謂的
because I just said I can't
因為我剛剛講說不能
need
需要
Cox2 to be selective
Cox2要選擇性的
Doubtful Fox2
以身有懷疑的Fox2
It started off fine
結果一開始還不錯
Since it was launched in 1999
因為1999年上市
then the most recent thing
然後最近的事情
But later found out that
可是後來發現說
Why
哎
have side effects
有副作用
Then there's a lot of legal action
然後開始有很多法律訴訟
So listed in 1999
所以1999年上市
So in 2004 when
所以在2004年的時候
Merck had to take him off the shelves automatically
默克只好自動把他下架
That's what people can see
那可是人也可以看到
2007 before they were taken off the shelves
2007年在他們下架之前
this number may
這個數字可能
may be a problem
可能有點問題
This number may not be 2007 either
這個數字可能也不是2007年
It was in 2001
就是在2001年的時候
his total
他的總
This can be sold for two hundred million dollars every year
這個每年可以賣到二數億美金
so he
所以他
Equal to the history of mankind
等於是人類有史以來
put this
把這種
very large sales
銷售量非常大的要
First off
第一次下架
is this virus
就是這個virus
then they have two versions
那他們有兩種版本
pharmaceutical factory is talking
藥廠是講說
just talking about this world
剛剛在說這個世界的東西
did notice this
的確有注意到這種
The risk of vascular disease
那個性血管疾病發生的風險
But our person is the experimental card
可是我們那個人是實驗物卡
Of course the manuscript is here
那當然原稿這邊
The patient told the pharmaceutical company that
病人這邊就告藥廠說
You are deliberately concealing your clinical
你是故意隱瞞你這個臨床時
So this is a bit of an argument
所以這個有一點爭執
what about the other one
那另外一個呢
It's this gray hot pharmaceutical factory
是這個灰熱的藥廠
What about his medication?
那他的藥物呢並沒有下架
Must be taken as directed by a physician
要必須醫師的指示服用
His sales that year turned out to be 3 billion US dollars
那年銷售額他原來是30億美金
Then what I just said
那後來剛剛講的這個
After the removal of the Morke drug
Morke藥物的下架以後
What about his medicine because it's not off the shelf?
他的藥物呢因為沒有下架
so recover slowly
所以慢慢的恢復
2 billion US dollars by 2006
到2006年還有20億美金
So there is still some controversy over this drug.
所以這個藥目前還是有一些爭執
Because everyone thinks there are still some
因為大家認為還是有一些
must be under control
必須在防治下
use under strict supervision
嚴格的監視下來的使用
i think i'm each for a while
我想我各好一段時間
ok let me tell you this
好我講這個
Killing Bean Wheat
殺力豆麥
This drug was developed in the 1950s
這個藥物在1950年代開發
At that time, he believed that there was a promotional effect
當時他認為有增進性的效果
And for this like a pregnant woman
而且對於這個像孕婦
when he has haematological symptoms
他有害血症狀的時候
He can stop vomiting
他可以止吐的效果
So this time is equal to
所以這個時候等於是
Pregnant women because there is such a magic drug
孕婦因為有這樣神邪藥
Because it has some anti-inflammatory and pain-relieving effects
因為他有一些消炎的止痛的效果
And there will be antiemetic
而且會有止吐
So become a lot of pregnant women
所以變成很多的孕婦
within that time period
在那段時間之內能夠服
That is to say, everyone is equal to
就是說大家等於是
Because blood is very
因為害血是很
that is to say it is a difficult
就是說是一個很難
very uncomfortable symptoms
很不舒服的症狀
So it becomes a saying that pregnant women should take it
所以變成說孕婦當大服用
But the problem was discovered later
可是問題後來發現
The child's birth deformity
這個小孩子的產生畸形
Look at the soles of this child's feet
你看這個小孩子這個腳掌
Suddenly there is one more beside him
他身邊就是突然多了一個
one toe out
一個腳趾出來
let you go out and see his other arm
讓你出去看他另外一個手臂
Only as long as the upper arm
只有長到只有上臂而已
This severe deformity makes this lethal bean wheat
這種嚴重的畸形讓這個殺力豆麥
in the 1950s
在1950年代
Discontinued in early 1960
1960年初就下架
probably in our world
大概在我們世界上
probably have time
大概有時間
about four or five years
大概四五年的時間
But it caused about 10,000 to 20,000
可是造成大概一萬到兩萬的
don't know
不懂
Model
機型的
right
對
used in the bathroom
在洗手間用了
Then later in the recent
那後來在最近的時候
They found that some tiredness curative effect
他們就發現有些疲憊的療效
I can't talk about the time relationship here.
那這邊時間關係我沒有辦法講
That is to say for some
就是說對於一些
symptoms of immunity or leprosy
免疫的症狀或是麻風病
autoimmune disease
引起了這個自體免疫性的疾病
it has some healing properties
它有一些治療效果
Then I won't talk about it here
那我這邊就不講了
In the end, I talked about some
那最後呢我講到一些
we just talked about the term new drug development
我們我剛剛講過新藥開發的名詞
What about new drug development?
那在新藥開發裡面呢
This is to introduce you
這個竟然跟各位來做介紹
We are now developing a drug
我們現在一個藥物的開發
In fact it is very strict
事實上是非常嚴謹的
then you have to because
那你要因為
we say
我們說
Clinical time is considered to be human body
臨床時間就算是人的身上
That
那
very strict
身上非常嚴謹的
So usually we need to have enough
所以通常我們需要有足夠的
This so-called pre-clinical
這個所謂的pre-clinical
data means clinical trials
data也就是說臨床實驗
these data
這些data
you have to collect
你要蒐集好
Let's say you want to tell people this
比如說你要告訴人家這個
toxicity of this molecule
這個分子的毒性
inside
裡面的
How are you doing with everyone?
跟大家做的東西是怎麼樣
To collect enough data
要收集足夠的data
You're going to send it to the FDA
你要送交給美國食品藥物觀念局
The audit thinks that this data
審核認為這個data
can be tested in humans
可以在人體這樣試驗的時候
He will follow you to do clinical trials
他才會遵循你做臨床實驗
This clinical trial actually has three phases
這個臨床實驗也事實上有三個階段
Have Face 1 Face 2 Face 3
有Face 1 Face 2 Face 3
Every stage is checked
每一個階段都有在把關
So it's actually a very rigorous process
所以事實上是個非常嚴謹的過程
you can't say casually
你不能說隨隨便便
You mean I'm like that right now
你就是說我馬上就像那個
Feed him straight away
馬上直接餵給他
it's okay to fuck dad
幹老爸沒事
in fact it's fine
事實上就沒事
Now after these 100 years
現在經過了這100年
I think we have a good idea for a process like this
我想我們對於這樣的過程
Right Reductive
對 還原型
Generally speaking
那一般來講
The so-called preclinical experimental data
所謂的臨床前的實驗data
basically because we have to do it before the animals
基本上因為我們在動物前要做
Not to be done before human experiments
不 在人體的實驗之前要做
So it's an animal model
所以是動物的model
So at this time you have to tell others about the experiment of reading Chinese
所以這時候你要告訴人家讀語的實驗
what happens with this drug
這個藥物會變成什麼事情
we are all metabolized
我們都心神代謝
pharmacokinetics
還有所謂藥物動力學
How does he supplement the various temperatures in the body
他怎麼在身體裡面各個氣溫的增補
you have to speak clearly
你都要講得清清楚楚
inside the animal
在動物裡面
can you do it with your heart
你可能以心來做嗎
explain clearly
解釋清楚
When it comes to clinical trials, there is a so-called internship
到了臨床實驗有所謂的實習
What about medical internships?
那醫療實習呢
with healthy people
是用健康的人
It is a healthy person to do the experiment
是健康的人來做實驗
Of course this pre-punctural inoculation
當然要把這pre-punctural接種
made in animals
在動物裡面做過的
Do it again
再做一次
After this is passed
那到了這個通過以後
You can enter the second and third stages
你才能進入到第二階段和第三階段
The second stage, the third stage
那第二階段、第三階段
what about this time
這個時候呢
is used on patients
就是用在病人身上
You have to look at him at this time
這個時候你就要看他
Is there any medical effect
到底有沒有醫療的效果
this is very important
這是很重要
And you have to give the doctor in the hospital
那而且你要給醫院的醫生
or you can't talk to him
或是你不能跟他講說
Which one is the drug and which one is the placebo
是哪一個是藥、哪一個是安慰劑
because you might
因為你可能
A group of patients is given vitamins
一組的病人是給他維他命
but you give him medicine
可是你給他藥
A group of his patients, that's the real drug in the experiment
他一組的病人那是真的藥在實驗
But doctors and nurses don't know
可是醫生和護士都不能知道
so they
所以他們
It's just that they just go over the table
就是他們只是按表去超客
To collect blood and urine from patients
去收集病人的血液、尿液
Then analyze his symptoms
然後他的症狀去做分析
Then if you wait until the third stage
然後如果等到第三階段的話
it's huge
這是很大規模
Experiments with potentially hundreds or thousands of people
可能數百人或數千人的實驗
At this time, the experiment will be compared with existing drugs
這個時候實驗就要跟現存的藥物
for comparison
來做比較
If there is a significant effect
如果有很明顯的效果
he will let
他才會讓
if no noticeable effect
如果沒有明顯的效果
or worse
或是比較更差的話
Then it is very likely that your previous efforts will be in vain.
那很可能你前面的努力就是白費
then if you are lucky
那如果你運氣好
Can you pass these experiments?
能不能通過這些實驗的話
You can talk to the US Food and Drug Administration
你才能跟美國的食品藥物管理局
or Taiwan's Food and Drug Administration
或是台灣的食品藥物管理局
Sent all is a New Drug application says
送交都是一個New Drug application說
I did all the data
我做了所有的data
I have human experiment data
我有人體實驗data
please take a good look
請你好好的看一看
then if you are satisfied
那如果你滿意的
you let me go public
你才容許我上市
So it's a very rigorous process
所以這是非常嚴謹的一個過程
That
那
So it's done like this
那所以這樣的做成呢
Why
為什麼
We say that this internship is more and more
我們說這個這個實習是越來
This time is getting longer and longer
這個時間上越拉越長
That means you spend more and more money
也就是說你要花越來越多錢
more and more time
越來越多時間
because of us
因為我們這個人
What about the human body?
人體呢
it's too early
這樣太不早了
So we have to test more things
所以我們要考越多東西
more and more
越來越多
So it turns into saying you need to pay more and more
所以變成說你花的錢要越來越多
A billion dollars may not have been needed ten years ago
十年前可能不需要十億美金
Now it may cost 1.2 to 1.5 billion
現在可能要十二到十五億
What about the average statistical average?
那一個平均統計上的平均呢
probably needed before
以前大概需要
five to eight years
五到八年
Then you may have to delay it for ten to twelve years
那你都可能要拖到十到十二年
So this is getting
所以這個是越來越
more and more money
越來越花錢
An increasingly risky Biannese
越來越有風險的Biannese
In addition, in fact, we are developing
另外呢事實上我們在研發過程中
There are some stimulating measures
有有一些刺激性的措施
like this orphan drug act
像這個孤兒藥法案
Open drug的Ecusivity
Open drug的Ecusivity
And Face trading
還有Face trading
for some
針對一些
rare disease
罕見疾病
how exciting
怎麼樣刺激
The pharmaceutical company asked him to invest
藥廠讓他去投資
or some medicine
或是說有一些藥
There are currently no effective treatments
目前沒有任何的有效療法
forFace trading
用Face trading
can get quickly
能夠很快得到
get certified and go public
得到認證然後上市
so these things i think
所以這些東西我想
Today I just use a very simple
今天我只是用一個很淺顯的
speech to everyone
演講來跟各位
to illustrate
來說明
Then I'll wait a minute. I don't know what's wrong with you.
那我等一下不知道各位有什麼問題
If you have any questions, I hope you can ask them
如果有任何問題的話希望各位能夠提出來
then i will talk about it today
那我今天就講到
Well, we thank Professor Lin for his very simple and wonderful speech
好我們謝謝林教授非常深入淺出而且精彩的演講
many stories
很多的故事
20 minutes is not enough, we are open to your questions
不夠的20幾分鐘我們開放各位的問題
Come
來
that you know is my question
那個您知道是我請教的問題
we don't have much time now let's just talk
我們現在時間不多我們簡單講
the avestin just mentioned
那個剛才講的那個avestin
that thing
那個東西啊
My eyes were in 2005
我這個眼睛在2005年的時候啊
that
那個
The main mirror vein of the left eye ruptured
左眼的那個主鏡脈破裂
that's painless
那不痛不癢
More than 28 days to see a doctor
超過了28天才去看醫生
So follow that eye
所以照著後來那個眼睛
Entire vision is gone
整個視力都不見了
that he said this in the early days
那個他說這個在早期的時候
at that Taipei Medical College
在那個台北醫學院
He said that with that similar treatment
他說用那個類似治療
Of course the spring of 2006
當然2006年的春天
Taipei Medical University gave up
台北醫學院放棄啦
He said there was no way to make a special trip
他說沒辦法夠專程到
He asked me about the dragon bug I told him to go to Taiwan Road
他問我叫他去台道的龍蟲
Because at that time there were only these two hospitals
因為那時候只有這兩家醫院
You can use that avestin when you get the government's punctuality
得到政府的準時可以用那個avestin
He said that the medicine was supposed to cure liver cancer
他說那個藥本來是要治肝癌的
But the effect is not good
但是效果不張
He said to use this to suppress this
他說用來這個抑制這個
Clean Tube Treatment Works Well
清潔管的治療效果很好
My eye became a ruptured vein
我那個眼睛就變成了靜脈破裂
So the human body is the source of many threats
所以人體是產生很多威脅管
But when the threat tube increases
但是威脅管增加的時候
a question that blood pressure
一個問題那個血壓
Soared to 63 at the highest
最高的時候飆到63
I feel like throwing up all day, I can't even fight
整天都想吐吐 戰都不能戰
He said in the early days before
他說在以前早期的話
If it doesn't work, it has to be removed.
就是不行的話已經要摘除
Then there is this medicine
那後來有這個藥
He hit this eye
他就打到這個眼睛裡面
That one dose is 28,000 yuan
那個一劑藥是2萬8千塊
Not covered by health insurance
健保不給負的
But the potion is not so big because the eyeballs are not dry
但是那個藥劑因為眼球沒有乾那麼大
so measles
所以就癖疹
Four people taking that one dose at the same time
四個人同時使用那個一劑藥
but after injection
但是注射了以後
after more than a year
經過了一年多
His vision is now restored
他的視力現在是恢復的
It's that transformation image
就是那個變勝形象
won't distort
不會扭曲
But that no way is no way liquid poison
但是那個沒有辦法是沒有辦法液毒
But now it reverts every three months
但是現在每三個月回整一次
that kid is normal
那個孩子都是很正常
He said that the medicine man will be fine
他說這個藥人就這樣就沒事了
or something later
還是以後有什麼事情
Sorry, I
對不起我
I said one of you, you got the data in the invasion
我說一你的那個你得到了invasion裡面的data
That Avasin just didn't talk
那個Avasin只好剛剛沒有講
Yeah, except for that swollen cow
對啦 除了在針對那個腫牛之外
It is another word that is useful in Yan Fu
它是另外一個對有用的字在嚴覆
Because our eyes are an interesting organ
因為我們眼睛是一個很有趣的器官
That is to say, generally speaking, if your body says that a blood vessel is broken,
就是說一般來講你身體如果說血管破裂
Then the body will have regenerative blood vessels to pre-close it
那身體就會有再生性的血管把它預合
But the eyes cannot grow blood vessels casually
可是眼睛是不能隨便長出血管的
Then your problem is that blood vessels grow out
那你的問題是血管長出來
it affects your vision
它影響到你的視力
The treatment of mentally retarded new blood vessels
那智障這種新生血管的治療
Avasin is a
Avasin是一種
In addition there are other
另外有其他
Like the Leise just mentioned, it is a very traditional medicinal bladder
像剛剛講的蕾色是很傳統的藥膀
photodynamic therapy
還有光動力的療法
It is the substance that takes it with a sense of light
它是把它用光明感的物質
Burn it in the way of ray light
用蕾色光的方式把它燒取
that's all
那都有
So now it means that there are two stalls of the same drug
那現在就是說有這兩攤同藥
The curative effect is pretty good
療效都蠻不錯的
Then you just talked about how Avasin has sequelae
那你剛剛講說Avasin怎麼會有後遺症
I don't think there will be any repercussions
我不覺得會有什麼後遺症
So it should be put here
所以應該放 here
This has passed very strict human experiments.
這個都已經通過很嚴格的那種人體實驗
I don't think so
我不覺得會
Because usually what I just mentioned means human experiments
因為通常我剛剛提過就是說人體的實驗
Although there are three stages
雖然有三階段
In fact there is a fourth stage
事實上是有第四個階段
Even if the first time is the FDA, he collects it at any time
第一次的就算是FDA他隨時收集
Even after the drug is on the market
就即使藥物上市以後
He wants to collect reports on the market at any time
他要隨時收集市場上的報告
If there is any adverse reaction, he will give a warning
有任何不良的反應他要提出警告
So I just drugged things like Lome Ting
所以我剛剛藥物像洛美婷那些東西
It's his after warning
就是他事後警告
Warning to the end there is no way
警告到最後沒有辦法
His drug seems to be like this, take it off the shelf
他藥物好像是這種把它下架
so i don't think abastin
所以我不覺得阿巴斯丁
Now their problem is the tumor
目前他們的問題是對腫瘤
Metastatic tumors do not respond significantly
轉移性的腫瘤沒有明顯的療效
Then I don't think there is any problem with the eyes
那我不覺得對眼睛有什麼任何問題
Thank you
謝謝你
Thanks
謝謝
Are there any other questions?
還有沒有其他的問題
later
後面
Excuse me about the H1N1 we have in the coming year
請問一下我們來年的那個H1N1
Did he go through this Face 1 2 3 like this
他的這個有沒有經過這個Face 1 2 3這樣
That vaccine is our own domestic vaccine
那個疫苗我們國產自己的疫苗
i believe there is
我相信是有
So in the end, did he follow the Protocol of Face 1 Face 2 Face 3?
那到底說他有沒有按照Face 1 Face 2 Face 3的Protocol
We say his watch is over the top
我們說他的案表要超客
For example, there is a prescribed number of people
比如說還有規定的人數
i am not defense
我不是國防
man at defense vaccine factory
國防疫苗工廠的人
i can't tell you
我沒有辦法跟你講
And if you know today our dean or anyone else
而且如果你今天我們院長或其他人知道
but i'm not in there
可是我不是在裡面的
I'm not fit for any criticism
我不適合做任何批評
Because any criticism I make is unfair to them
因為我做任何批評都對他們不公平
so i have no choice
所以我沒有辦法
I have no data to tell you
我沒有data辦法跟你講
OK
好不好
Erase you just mentioned
剛剛你提到的Erase
Geneva Jaffet
Genev Jaffet
It seems to be off the market in the United States
好像在美國是下市的
That's a relatively new drug now
那現在比較新的藥物
The second generation is Tasiva
第二代是Tasiva
It is a branch of EGF
就是EGF的一支物
You say Erase
你說Erase
Erase seems to be useful for Asians
Erase好像在亞洲人士有用
That's from EGF
那個是EGF的
Yes, that's EGF
對 那是EGF
it seems so
好像是這樣
no need to eat
沒有需要吃
But he is relatively useless to Europeans and Americans
可是他在對歐美人士比較沒有用
Erase is for Long Cancer
Erase是對Long Cancer
They found that he was committed to a less high percentage in Europe and America
他們發現他致力在歐美的比例沒有那麼高
but in asia
可是在亞洲
is very useful
是很有用的
Sixty to seventy percent of people are polluted
有六七十%的人是被polluted
that's just because
那只是因為
the reaction to the medicine
那對藥的反應
but did not say
可是沒有說下
That is to say, he generally
就是說他一般來講說
Because his success rate of self-reliance rate is not so high
因為他的自力率的成功率沒有那麼高
He may have other alternative medications that can be substituted
他可能會有其他替代性的藥物可以取代
You also mentioned that coach
那張教練你也提到
Avestan的Avestan
Avestan的Avestan
As far as I know it is for that Metastatic
據我了解是對那個Metastatic
Breast Cancer is useless
Bress Cancer是沒有用的
you are right
你講的是對的
but not for all
可是不是對全部的
All of these transfers are useless
這些轉移的全部沒有用
Just for Breast Cancer
只是針對Bress Cancer
Okay, thank you
好謝謝
that has one
那個有一個
these nutrients
這些營養
Nutrients
營養品
For example like Glucosamine
比如說像Glucosamine
In fact, many of us
其實很多我們
A while ago with Sydney Heck
前一陣子跟Sydney Heck
we are chatting
我們在聊天
He is an American expert
他是一個美國的專家
He said they were liars
他說這些都是騙子
no use at all
根本沒有用
Because of that Glucosamine
因為那個Glucosamine
we should do it
應該我們要去弄
Sati Glucosamine
Satio Glucosamine
So the dean has been talking to me for a long time
所以院長已經跟我講很久
open a company
開一個公司
to turn Glucosamine into
去把Glucosamine把他變成
He said that's easy, get it done
他說那個很簡單這個弄下來
i squeezed you
我有給你擠過
let's start a company
我們趕快去開一個公司
that's what works
那個才是有效的
Because of that Glucosamine
因為那個Glucosamine
That solubility is not right
那個solubility也不對
After that
然後是
Wisdom
智慮大力
But say so
不過這樣子說
I'm not fair either
我也不公平
My wife wants me to eat a few pills every day
我太太每天要我吃幾顆
so
所以
I still listen to my wife
我還是很聽我太太的話
but this
不過這個
have some nutritious food
有一些營養食品
actually
其實
Not necessarily the one they were talking about
不見得是他們講的那個
yes and
對 而且
very cheap because
非常便宜 因為
Glucosamine
Glucosamine
how he
他怎麼
he is from that
他是從那個
Shrimp shells, crab shells
蝦殼啊 螃蟹殼
people are different
人家不一樣
then decompose it
然後把它衰解
So it's actually cheap
所以其實他那個很便宜
very cheap stuff
很便宜的東西
but you can see
可是你可以看到
a can
一罐
probably both
可能都
good
好
yes
對啊
thousands of dollars is expensive
上千塊很貴
but
但是
unjustified violence
不正當的暴力
Fairness should take care of it
公平會應該要管一下
i have two questions
我有兩個問題
Just now you said Glucosamine
剛剛你們說Glucosamine
OK then if
OK 那如果
like us
像我們人
You added because you said it was just cartilage
你補充 因為你說它只是軟骨
Cartilage is your single component
軟骨是你單一的 component
Is it useful to add a single thing?
你補充單一的東西那有用嗎
The second question is, just now you said
第二問題是 剛剛你說
in human business
在 human business
It is drug discovery
就是 drug discovery
You want a lot of SOP
你要很多 SOP
Cleaner trade phase one phase two phase three
Cleaner trade phase one phase two phase three
if a drug
如果一個藥物
it has passed in the usa
它在美國已經通過了
它的 phase one phase two phase three
它的 phase one phase two phase three
Do we have to do the same procedure in Taiwan?
那在台灣是不是也要做同樣的 procedure
Because of different races?
因為不同的人種嗎
I answer your second question
我回答你第二個問題
Usually it means this clinical trial
通常就是說 this clinical trial
tantamount to saying
等於是說
So this is a couple of issues
所以這有幾個 issue
very good question
問題非常好
That is to say today a clinical trial
就是說 今天一個 clinical trial
it must be in
它必須在
because if you take into account the issue of race
因為如果你考慮到人種的問題
Different races react differently to drugs
不同的人種的藥物的反應是不一樣
So it must be in a different area of ​​the drug
所以它必須在不同的地區藥物
able to do some clinical trials
能夠做一些 clinical trial
It collects enough data
它的搜集足夠的 data
it can know to say
它才能夠知道說
There are different reactions in different regions
在不同的地區是有不一樣的反應
The second is to say
那第二個就是說
The understanding of the second consideration is that
第二個考量的理解是說
In fact these protocols
事實上這些 protocol
like you said
就像你講的
in fact there is
這事實上是有
it has certain rules
它有一定的規矩
that now
那現在
There are many medicines in Taiwan now
現在台灣有很多藥藥
Come to Taiwan to do CleanLTry
來台灣做CleanLTry
In fact, we are follow US FDA
那事實上我們是follow美國FDA
the prologue
的prologue
we think his procigil
我們認為他的procigil
to his program to do
到他的程序去做
So in the future these things
所以將來這些東西的話
It is the US FDA, which will naturally pass
就是美國FDA那自然會通過
If we say that some countries today
那如果說今天有一些國家
like japan or other countries
像日本或其他國家
Their standards are different from FDA
他們的標準是跟FDA不一樣的
Then he passed the experiment in Japan
那他日本通過的實驗
He's going to America to do it all over again
他還要到美國重新做一次
Because he adopts different standards
因為他採取的標準是不一樣的
So it turns into whether you want to be in line with international standards
所以變成說你要不要跟國際接軌
just like sync
就跟同步一樣
That's relatively easy
那這樣子比較不費事
Then we follow FDA standards to do
那我們followFDA的標準去做
OK
好不好
Then your first question was
那你剛剛第一個問題是
Say you Google
說你又Google
Yeah
對對對
can't that be
那不可以這樣嗎
No
沒有
Because of the Google gas you just mentioned
因為你剛剛講的Google gas
The other one is Google gas
另外一個是Google gas
of our body
我們身體的
or Google gas
或是Google gas
on google
Google上面
He can sell people very expensive
他可以把人家賣很貴
is worth not staying pathological
是值得不留病理
So can't hope for a long time that I can start a company
所以不能長一時間希望我能夠開公司
I also hope that
我也希望
Ask Professor Lin
請教林教授
the one you just mentioned
你剛剛提到的那個
Astilin is extracted from that Liushi
阿斯啼林是用那個流氏萃取出來的
right
對
and that
還有那個
That Purple Mountain Lip of the Pacific Purple Mountain
太平洋紫山的那個紫山唇
then ask you
那請教你
that this
那這個
Medicines like this belong to natural medicine
這樣子的藥是屬於自然醫學的藥物
still belongs to western medicine
還是屬於西藥
Another problem is
還有一個問題就是
About your anti-cancer and another kind of that
有關你那個抗癌還有一種那個
Anti-cancer drugs are extracted from customs
抗癌妥是習俗萃取出來的
Then do you think this anti-cancer drug is effective?
那你認為這個抗癌妥的藥效
what you just said
跟你剛剛講的
The effects of Asti and Aretha
阿斯啼跟艾瑞莎他們的效果
which one is better
比較的哪一種會比較好
Thanks
謝謝
The second question is because of that
第二個問題因為那個
Because many medicines have different injection chambers
因為很多藥它有不一樣的注射商會
have a name or we don't
要有名字或我們沒有
i don't know what it is
我不知道它是什麼東西
so i can't answer you
所以我沒有辦法回答你
I have no way to answer the second question just mentioned
剛剛講第二個問題我沒有辦法回答
the first one
那第一個
you speak so-so
你講的一般
We just talked about paper mountain lip or aspirin
剛才講紙山唇或是阿斯比林
It is from the natural temperature
它是從天然溫稅去
But you can't say I'm today because it works
可是你不能說我今天因為它有效
as people said before
就像之前人家講說
Anti-cow feeling should be made from star anise
抗牛感要從八角做出來
just ran to buy star anise
就跑去買八角
logic doesn't work like this
邏輯這樣是不通的
Why?
為什麼?
because you go straight to
因為你直接去
I induce you to give birth
我引你產
you eat directly
你直接吃
Assuming there are vegetarian skins to eat
假設有素皮可以吃的話
The problem is that it has different ingredients in it
問題是它裡面有不同的成分
you eat
你吃
you eat these ingredients
你把這些成分吃下去
In addition, we usually
另外就是我們通常
These studies usually brittle these things out
這些研究通常把這些東西脆以出來
and you know the amount
而且你知道它的量
If you directly from the natural temperature tax
如果你直接從天然溫稅
when your medicine
當你的藥材的話
that dose is very low
那個藥量是非常低的
Then you have different other ingredients
那你又有不同的其他的成分
this is very complicated
這個是很複雜的
So this is where Chinese medicine differs from Western medicine.
所以這個是中醫跟西醫不一樣的地方
words of Chinese medicine
中醫的話
it is to emphasize this
它是強調這個
The effect of combining different ingredients
不同的成分結合的效果
That's Western medicine, it's
那可是西醫它是
it's clear
它很清楚
because you look at the single ingredient
因為你看看單一的成分
but it tells you
可是它跟你講
I want to experiment with cells
我要有細胞的實驗
experiments with animals
有動物的實驗
experiments with humans
有人體的實驗
These currencies also have my ability
這些通貨也有我才能
can make you eat
能夠讓你去吃
This logic is different from philosophy
這個邏輯跟哲學是不一樣的東西
but i mean
不過我的意思是說
He is extracted like this
他是這樣子已經萃取出來
It also belongs to the natural medicine medicine
他還屬於是歸類於自然醫學藥物
or western medicine
還是西藥物
Western medicine
西藥
Okay, thank you
好 謝謝
Yes, he is already a single compound
對 他是已經是單一的化合物了
do it with a single compound
用單一化合物去做
This continues some of the clinical careers above
這個繼續上面的一些臨床事業
So he is already a thing of western medicine
所以他已經是西藥的一個東西
Western medicine
西藥
right
對
And the molecule will be modified again like just now
而且像剛剛這個分子還會再被修改過
Like that Hoffmann just now for his neighborhood
就像剛剛那個Hoffmann他為了他附近
he did some chemistry with him
他把他做一些化學反應
he still modified
他還是修改過
what do you think
你怎麼看一看
you, let me add
你那個我補充一下
The wash you just asked about
你剛才問的那個洗術
That's Tob Teigen
那他是Tob Teigen
Temple Teigen kind of thing
Temple Teigen那種東西
Then his mechanism of action is different from that of Zishanchun.
那他作用機制跟這個紫山純的不一樣
Texel acts on the microtubules he just mentioned
Texel是作用在他剛才講的微管
The one from Jubilant
Jubilant的那個
that synthetic
那個合成的
that wash this
那洗術的這個
is an efficiency that acts on the action of DNA
是作用在DNA的作用的一個效率
These two are not the same
這兩個不太一樣
He is in our Converse land
他在我們這個康維土
In Taiwan, it is currently the health insurance index
在我們臺灣目前是健保指數
used for a while
是用在一會兒
no
不是
it's the large intestine
是那個大腸
Fatty bowel cancer
大腸脂腸癌
Feel sorry
抱歉
It is used in colorectal adipose bowel cancer
是用在大腸脂腸癌
health care index
健保指數
Thanks
謝謝
Professor Lin, ask me
那個林教授請教一下
two questions
兩個問題
first question
第一個問題
Can Painkillers Harm Your Liver?
止痛藥會不會傷肝
second question
第二個問題
My mother has been suffering from severe gout recently
家母最近因為痛風非常嚴重
I took her to see a doctor at Chenda Hospital
我帶她去陳大醫院看病
As a result, the doctor
結果醫生一開
just opened that rib lip
就開了那個肋骨唇
I freaked out when I saw the rib lip
我一看到肋骨唇我就嚇一跳
And open four
而且一開開四顆
So eat four at a time
所以一次要吃四顆
Each tablet is about 5mg
每一顆大概是5mg
then i want to ask
那我想請問
We are generally not on the rib lip
我們一般不是對肋骨唇
have a bad impression
有一種不好的印象
Said to eat too much
說吃多了
not good for health
對身體不好
can you explain
能不能解釋一下
I'm still emphasizing
我還是去強調
not a doctor
不是醫生
Not a doctor at National Taiwan University Hospital
不是台大醫院醫生
I'm just a little researcher
我只是一個小小研究員
so i didn't really didn't
所以說我沒有真的沒有
and i didn't see your mother
而且我沒看到你媽媽
What kind of symptoms does she have?
她到底什麼樣症狀
I really can't make this diagnosis
我真的是沒辦法做這種診斷
It's really something that has no limited manpower.
真的是沒人力有限的東西
there is no way
是沒有辦法
I'm just asking about steroids
我只是請教內固醇這個東西
tell you
對你講
The problem is Steroid it has a different effect
問題是Steroid它有不同的效果
And it often makes some
而且它身體裡面常常做一些
adjustment
的調節
So you usually have to be very careful when using
所以使用上通常是要非常小心
then i guess maybe
那我再猜可能
I don't know if it's because of your mother
我不知道是不是因為你媽媽
have specific symptoms
有特別的症狀
so the doctor has
所以醫生有
There will also be such a class assessment achievement
還會開出這樣的一個類估成就
I think you should be direct
我是覺得你應該直接
do one with the doctor
跟醫生做一個
to communicate face to face
當面對面的去溝通
this is better
這樣是比較好
I can't give you a split opinion
我不能提供你分合的意見
what was your first question
那你剛剛第一個問題是什麼
Can Painkillers Hurt Your Liver?
止痛藥會傷肝嗎
That painkiller hurts the liver
那個止痛藥會傷肝
This is on the side of the Puna phlegm
這個在那個普拿痰那邊
There is an explanation
有做說明
If you have read relevant information
如果你有去看相關的資料的話
But usually
不過通常來講
Propula
以普拿痰
His scar basically has two prerequisites
他的傷痕基本上有兩個先決條件
the first one you want to overdose
第一個你要overdose
Because generally speaking, the dosage of Pranaden
因為一般來講普拿登他的使服用量
If as far as I know it is 500mg
如果據我知道是500mg
then you
那你這樣
Usually the dosage can reach 67 times
通常在服用量可以到67倍
He's just starting to have scars
他才開始有傷痕的作用
So two prerequisites
所以兩個先決條件
one is that you want to overdose
一個是你要過量
Basically if you follow your prescription for a day
基本上如果你按照一天處方
you can never overdose
你絕對不可能過量
The second is that you have to cooperate with alcohol
第二個是你要配合酒精
it means you drink
就是說你喝酒
And then eat Proden
然後還吃普拿登
that will scar
那個才會傷痕
But generally speaking, the effect of Proton
不過一般來講普拿登的效果
Usually low value
通常護重值滿低的
unless you have these two conditions
除非你有這兩個條件
He gets scars when he cooperates
配合的時候他才會傷痕
i want to return to
我想回歸到
The period film of our nutrition
我們營養的期膜
That is to say, health medicine does not
就是說健康藥不要
Then my question is
那我的問題是
such as sleeping pills
比如說安眠藥
or political economy
或者是政經濟
generally
一般
when the doctor prescribed
就是醫生開的時候
patients usually
病人通常
I still wish I could not eat it.
還是很希望能夠不吃就不是
for fear of being dependent
因為怕會依賴
Then they'd like to be able to use another way
那他們會希望能夠用別種方式
Also all I know is
另外我所知道的就是
A recent friend, Mr. He
最近一個朋友他先生
Because I moved for a long time after taking the medicine
因為吃了正經劑之後又移久了
Finally sent to the emergency room
最後送急診
But the one in therapy
但是在治療當中的那個
The doctor in the emergency room gave him another shot
急診的醫生又給他一次正經劑
He turned into a vegetable
結果他就變成植物人了
So now I take the medicine
所以我現在就吃藥之後
Generally, I still hope that I can not take medicine without taking medicine.
一般還是希望能夠不吃藥就不吃藥
I have the same opinion
我也是完全同眼看法
because I want
因為我自己要
Sometimes the Central Plains Institute is under great pressure
中原院有時候壓力大的時候
Can't sleep or keep sleeping
睡不著還是要維持睡眠
you are stressed
你的壓力大了
So my own feeling is that later I relied on exercise
所以我自己的感覺是後來我是靠運動
because it means you can't sleep
因為就是說你睡不著
Maybe you have too much energy
可能是你精力太旺盛
Later, I developed the habit of exercising myself
後來我自己養成運動的習慣
10:00 p.m. Natural men want to sleep
晚上10點10點自然男就想要睡覺
that's the best way
那是最好的方法
So my own experience is that
所以我自己的經驗是說
of course i will agree with you
當然我會同意你
Unless if you really need to use
除非如果你真的需要使用的時候
I would suggest you to see a doctor for an IQ test
我就建議你要找醫生去做智商
Now Taiwan's problem is
那現在台灣的問題就是
Because health care products you know you need to know
因為健保品你知道要知道
you go to the doctor
你去看醫生
Of course the hospital will give you 3 minutes and 5 minutes
醫院當然都給你3分鐘5分鐘
about to be kicked out
就要被趕出來
So if you have an IQ
那如果說你有一個可以智商
subject doctor
對象的醫生
talk to him well
好好跟他講
Because usually doctors start firing
因為通常醫生要開始開除
basically knowing your medical history
基本上是了解你的病史
Or do you have any of these techniques for taking medicine
或是你有沒有服用藥的這些技術
or even have an allergy
或是甚至有對藥過敏
Like academician Zhong, a member of our hospital
像我們醫院裡面成員重院士
His allergy to that allergy drug
他對於那種過敏藥物的過敏
and good research
還有很好的研究
You need to understand these things
那這些東西都要了解
Only then can the medicine that really suits you be dismissed
才能開除真的適合你的藥
right now we just talked about
就現在我們剛剛講過
personalized therapy
personalized therapy
personalized medicine
就是個人化的醫療
is the most important
才最重要
The health insurance system, I suggest
健保的制度,我是建議說
You should find a family doctor you can trust
你應該找到一個可以信賴的家庭醫生
He can do some better counseling
他可以做一些比較好的諮詢
In this case, you will not use enough drugs
這樣的話,你對藥物的使用會不會不夠
i don't think it will go wrong
我想還不會出差錯
Then he has someone, you are after
那他跟有一位,你是在追求的
you fade
你掉色
i have an idea that you are
我有個想法,你就是
What is the so-called voter medicine?
所謂的選民藥是指什麼
It means that his patent has passed zero, so it can be opened
是指說他專利起零過了,所以可以開放
Drugs that everyone can produce
讓大家都可以生產的藥物
Not wrong, because of the so-called professional, because he spent a lot of time opening the pharmaceutical factory
沒有錯,因為所謂的專業,因為藥廠他花了很多時間開放
So usually the patent protection period is about 12 to 15 years.
所以通常專利的保護期大概就是12到15年
you start
你開始
After registering this patent, you can get a reward and then sell it
去註冊這個專利以後,到你可以賞次,然後可以賣
So sometimes after too long a delay, he really
所以有時候一拖太久,他真的
Can sell the whole world alone only you can sell
能夠獨賣全世界只有你能夠賣
that may not be a few years
那可能沒有幾年
so he gave you a while
所以說他給你一段時間
But a patent is about to fall
可是一段專利要落
This patent has passed
這個專利起過了
All pharmaceutical factories are put into production
所有藥廠都投入生產
So generally speaking, it should be cheaper to learn folk medicine
所以通常來講學民藥應該是比較便宜
Because everyone can produce
因為大家都可以生產
It should be relatively simple to compete in the next grid
下格競爭這個應該是比較簡單
So Suscanol is
所以Suscanol就是
Is it the unobtainable scholar medicine?
不拿得的學民藥是不是
I know it's Panodol
我知道是Panodol
I don't know if there are other
我不知道有沒有其他
Shoppers
Panodol
Astamino Fan
阿斯塔米諾Fan
this medicine you
這個藥啊你
I have a cold recently
我最近因為感冒
so i go buy this
所以我去買這個
The blessing hat is to make up for it
福帽就是補拿得
You open that medicine list and look at it
你把那個藥單打開來看
at least twenty names
至少有二十種名字
so
所以
Just say a name, it doesn't have to be
隨便講一個名字不一定是
That's because the blessing hat has
那因為那個福帽裡面它裡面有
neutralize symptoms
中和症狀
so it curbs your runny nose
所以它會抑制你流鼻水
Stop knocking
止磕
It's got a bunch so it's got a lot of medicine in it
它有一大堆所以裡面加了大多藥
the same medicine
同一個藥
that
那個
that drug
那個藥物啊
its name
它的名字
There are twenty-three kinds of names because different names came out.
因為不一樣的名字出來的所以有二十三種名字
So everyone is probably saying the same thing
所以大家講的可能是一樣的
have a different name
要有交不同名稱
OK, is there anything else?
好 那還有沒有其他
the student
這位學生
here then please
在這裡 然後請
hello i ask two
你好 我問兩個
I ask two questions
我問一下兩個問題
maybe my question is a bit stupid
可能我的問題有點愚蠢
that is
就是說
Why are there so many drugs
為什麼有不少的藥物
It is metabolized to go out in the end
它是以元太代謝到底外出去
Then when it biochemically reacts
然後它在生化反應的時候
No, structural changes cannot happen immediately
是不 馬上是不能發生結構上的改變
first question
第一個問題
then the second question
然後第二個問題
can i go over that spring part again
我能不能再講一次那個Spring的部分
that is
就是說
Because I have researched that Reynolds backsong
因為我有研究一下那個雷諾斯正後曲
then i should say
那我應該是說
that
那個
Because I went to study that
因為我是去有研究那個
the capital compound
那個資族化合物
solid compound
就是固成類化合物
because it has slow
因為它有緩非合
then i want to ask
然後我想問說
Can you say Spring again
可不可以再說一次Spring
how to prove
要是怎麼樣去證明說
It is a non-ethnic compound
它是一個非資族化合物
But it can also achieve
可是它也可以達到
Anti-addiction effect
抗發癮的效果
first question
第一個問題
drug metabolism
藥物的代謝
usual practice
通常一般的做法
he didn't
他沒有
take a medicine
一個藥吃進去
Then from the original molecule
然後會從原來的分子
run out like this
這樣跑出去
absolutely impossible
絕對不可能
usually especially some
通常尤其是有一些
water-based drugs
出水性的藥物
Usually above he will do some oxidation
通常上面他會做一些氧化
usually
一般來講
The approach is that he wants to be on top of this drug
做法是他要在這個藥物上面
do the same similar
做同類似的類似
he is going to track
他要去追蹤
e.g. in blood
比如說在血液
he wants to clarify
他要去分明
Then purify
然後純化
to identify what he has become
去鑑定他變成什麼樣的
what kind of biochemical reaction
做什麼樣的生化反應
that is in
那個是在
Pri-Kin-Yo-Three
Pri-Kin-Yo-Tri
In fact he was
事實上他有在
money
Kin-Yo-Tri
FaceOne, he is going to do these studies now
FaceOne他現在要做這些study
this must be done
這是一定要做的
so impossible
所以不可能
most will not
大部分不會
Running out like this
原來的樣子這樣跑出來
absolutely not
絕對不會
the second
第二個
you talk about lace dragon
你講到蕾絲龍
because you signed a lot
因為你簽上很多
Chinese translated name
中文的翻譯名字
we have no way
我們沒有辦法
so we can
所以我們可以
Let's talk about this in private, okay?
私下再來講這個事情好不好
if you need me
如果說你需要我
I will meet in Aspen
我會在阿斯編面
to explain
做講解
otherwise i
不然我
he was everyone's time
他當了大家的時間
We can talk to you directly
我們可以直接跟你們對象
OK
好不好
if there are no other questions
如果沒有其他的問題
do we thank you again
我們是不是再次感謝
pay attention to what we say
我們人家說的注意
Thanks
謝謝